本字幕由 assrt.net 字幕智能体自主生成。
[鼓聲響起]
[drums playing]
[《不可能的任務》主題曲響起]
[ Mission: Impossible theme playing]
[伊森] 我們在陰影中生死
[Ethan] We live and die in the shadows,
為了我們珍視的人
for those we hold close
也為了我們素未謀面的人
and for those we never meet.
[所羅門·萊恩] 你一直恐懼的終局即將來臨
[Solomon Lane] The end you always feared is coming.
[班吉] 反上帝
[Benji] The Anti-God.
[國家安全局代表] 這個「智體」有多重人格
[NSA representative] This "entity" has multiple personalities.
[鄧林格] 你是說這東西有它自己的思想？
[Denlinger] You’re telling me this thing has a mind of its own?
[班吉] 一個具自我意識、自我學習、吞噬真相的數字寄生蟲
[Benji] A self-aware, self-learning, truth-eating digital parasite
正在侵蝕整個網路空間
infesting all of cyberspace.
[鄧林格] 一個無所不在、無處可尋且沒有核心的敵人
[Denlinger] An enemy that is everywhere and nowhere and has no center.
[國家安全局代表] 耐心地傾聽、閱讀、觀察
[NSA representative] Patiently listening, reading, watching.
[國家偵察局代表] 年復一年地蒐集我們最深層的個人秘密
[NRO representative] Harvesting our deepest personal secrets for years.
[國防情報局代表] 能夠蠱惑、脅迫、賄賂或偽裝成任何人
[DIA representative] Able to beguile, blackmail, bribe or be anyone it wants.
[班吉] 伊森 那不是我！你在跟智體對話
[Benji] Ethan, that is not me! You’re talking to the Entity.
[基特里奇] 誰能掌控智體 誰就掌控真相
[Kittridge] Whoever controls the Entity controls the truth.
[國家安全域性代表] 最安全的資料中心已被入侵併破壞
[NSA representative] ...most secure data centers are breached and corrupted.
[聯合特種作戰司令部代表] 智體將精準掌握
[JSOC representative] The Entity will know precisely
如何瓦解我們的每一處優勢
how to undermine our every strength.
[國防情報局代表] 把我們的盟友變成敵人……
[DIA representative] Turn our allies into enemies...
[聯合特種作戰司令部代表] 並利用我們的每一個弱點
[JSOC representative] And exploit our every weakness.
[國防情報局代表] ……並把我們的敵人變成侵略者
[DIA representative]...and our enemies into aggressors.
[班吉] 一股不可阻擋的毀滅力量 會將一切夷為平地
[Benji] An unstoppable force of destructive power that would just lay waste to everything.
[白寡婦] 世界正在改變 真相正在消逝
[White Widow] The world is changing. Truth is vanishing.
戰爭即將來臨
War is coming.
[錄音中的埃裡卡] 晚上好 伊森
[Erika on recording] Good evening, Ethan.
我是你的總統
This is your president.
既然你不肯回復其他人
Since you won’t reply to anyone else,
我想我該直接聯絡你
I thought I’d reach out directly.
首先 我要感謝你
First, I want to thank you
終生奉獻與永不停歇的付出
for a lifetime of devoted and unrelenting service.
如果沒有你和你的團隊不懈的奉獻
Were it not for the tireless dedication of you and your team,
地球將會是一個截然不同的地方
the Earth would be a very different place.
甚至可能根本就不復存在
It might not even be here at all.
你冒過的每一次險……
Every risk you’ve taken...
你在戰場上失去的每一位戰友……
every comrade you’ve lost in the field...
你做出的每一次個人犧牲……
every personal sacrifice you made...
都為這個世界迎來了又一次日出
has brought this world another sunrise.
歲月流轉 自你因緣際會加入我們至今已滿35年
It’s been 35 years since circumstances brought you to us
當時你面臨著抉擇
and you were given the choice,
自從不可能任務情報局把你拯救
since the IMF saved you
避免了牢獄之災
from a life in prison.
儘管你從未遵從命令
And though you never followed orders,
但你從未讓我們失望
you never let us down.
[無聲對話]
[no audible dialogue]
你始終是出類拔萃的精英……
You were always the best of men...
在最艱難的時刻
in the worst of times.
[無聲對話]
[no audible dialogue]
我現在需要你再次成為那樣的人
I need you to be that man now.
自你在奧地利避開抓捕後的幾個月裡
In the months since you evaded capture in Austria,
網路世界的每一個角落都被那個吞噬真相、
every corner of cyberspace has been infested by the truth-eating,
被我們稱為智體的寄生人工智慧所侵蝕
parasitic A.I. known to us as the Entity.
在它的影響下
Under its influence,
全球的數字資訊都已被篡改
digital information has been corrupted worldwide.
國家和人民不再知道該相信什麼
Nations and people no longer know what to believe.
敵意、
Antagonism,
侵略和戒嚴成為了世界新秩序
aggression and martial law are the new world order.
智體利用這種人人自危的恐慌氛圍
Exploiting this paranoid atmosphere,
煽動了一個末日邪教
the Entity has inspired a doomsday cult
其信徒致力於透過人類滅絕
with acolytes devoted to ridding the world of corruption
來消除世間的腐敗
through human extinction.
神對諾亞說：“看哪……”
And He said unto Noah, "Behold..."
“我要使洪水降在地上
"I will bring a flood upon the earth
毀滅凡有血氣的 ”
to destroy all flesh."
原子之子將從廢墟中崛起
The children of the atom shall rise from the ashes.
而智體將幫助他們重建
And the Entity will help them rebuild.
[埃裡卡] 這些狂熱分子正秘密滲透進執法部門、
[Erika] These fanatics are secretly infiltrating every level of law enforcement,
政府和我們軍隊的各個層級
government and our military,
致力於服務他們數字主人的終極目標
devoted to serving their digital master’s ultimate goal.
我們掌控智體的唯一希望
Our only hope of controlling the Entity
在於尋找它的最初原始碼
relies on finding its original source code.
如果有人知道這段程式碼的下落 那就是這個人
If anyone knows the whereabouts of this code, it’s this man.
他的身份、他的過去、甚至他的存在都被抹去了
His identity, his past, his very existence have been erased,
這表明他現在或曾經與智體同謀
suggesting he is or was in league with the Entity.
奧地利當局拘留了他的同謀
Austrian authorities have his accomplice in custody.
但她拒絕向我們透露任何事情
But she has refused to tell us anything.
這又讓我們繞回到了你身上
Which brings us back to you.
你手裡有一把鑰匙 被認為是我們在獲取
You are in possession of a key believed to be a vital component
智體原始碼鬥爭中的關鍵元件
in our struggle to acquire the Entity’s source code.
然而你拒絕歸隊交出它
Yet you refuse to come in,
擔心任何政府都會將這邪惡的人工智慧武器化
fearing any government will weaponize this malicious A.I.
用來對抗世界上的其他人
against the rest of the world.
相反 你決心消滅智體
Instead you’ve resolved to kill the Entity,
這種魯莽的行為會引發網路世界的徹底毀滅
a reckless act that would trigger the total annihilation of cyberspace.
這將徹底摧毀全球經濟
This would eradicate the global economy,
使世界陷入無休止的戰爭和饑荒
plunging the world into war and famine without end.
特工亨特 伊森
Agent Hunt. Ethan.
請放棄抵抗
Please surrender.
否則世人的鮮血都將沾在你的手上
Or the blood of the world will be on your hands.
本條資訊將在五秒後自動銷燬
This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
回家吧 伊森
Come home, Ethan,
把那把鑰匙帶給我們
and bring us that key.
[人群呼喊] 徹底結束它！徹底結束它！
[crowd chanting] End it now! End it now!
徹底結束它！徹底結束它！徹底結束它！
End it now! End it now! End it now!
[呼喊聲持續]
[chanting continues]
徹底結束它！徹底結束它！徹底結束它！
End it now! End it now! End it now!
[呼喊聲持續]
[chanting continues]
[剎車聲刺耳]
[brakes squeal]
嘿 伊森
Hey, Ethan.
嘿 盧瑟
Hey, Luther.
[盧瑟] 抱歉這兒簡陋了點 麗思卡爾頓酒店全都訂滿了
[Luther] Sorry about the decor. The Ritz was booked solid.
嗯 掛點窗簾 放幾個抱枕 然後……
Well, some drapes, a few throw pillows, and...
對 來個迷你酒吧
Yeah, a minibar.
還有桌球檯
Foosball table.
嘿 兄弟 嘿
Hey, bro. Hey.
很高興看到你還活得好好的
It’s always good to see you on the right side of the grass.
我擔心你拼得太兇了
I’m worried you’re working too hard.
別操心老盧瑟
Don’t worry about ol’ Luther.
好的
Okay.
那麼 你查到了什麼？
So, what did you manage to find out?
很多
A lot.
比我預想的要多得多
More than I bargained for.
那麼 下一步怎麼做？
So, what’s the play?
[伊森] 首先
[Ethan] First,
我們必須找到蓋布瑞爾
we have to find Gabriel.
[盧瑟] 我們怎麼找他？
[Luther] How do we find him?
你會背叛我們的
You will betray us
因為他饒了你一命
because he spared your life.
[槍聲]
[gunfire]
[法語] 站住 站住
[in French] STOP. STOP.
[英語] 等等 等等 等等！
[in English] Wait, wait, wait!
為什麼……
Why...
你為什麼饒了我一命？
did you spare my life?
[英語] 等等 等等 等等！
[in English] Wait, wait, wait!
你要是通報上去 世界就全完了——就這麼簡單
You call that in, it’s the end of the world-- simple as that.
你是德加 對吧？
Degas, isn’t it?
時間一分一秒在流逝
Clock is running.
你要是把我們抓回去 這地球上就沒人能阻止它了
You take us in, there won’t be anyone on Earth who can stop it.
你內心深處也明白這一點
There’s a part of you that knows that.
我看得出來
I can see it.
看在上帝的份上 相信他吧！等等 等等 別！
For God’s sake, just trust him! Wait, wait, no!
沒事 沒事！
It’s okay, it’s okay!
德加 沒事的 這事不分國界
Degas, it’s okay. There’s no nations on this one.
沒有對立的意識形態 沒有教條
There’s no rival ideologies, no dogma.
這隻取決於誰能保持清醒 誰會陷入恐慌
It’s who keeps their head and who panics.
智體想讓你害怕 它想讓我們所有人都害怕
The Entity wants you scared, it wants us all scared.
它想讓我們分崩離析
It wants us divided.
它想讓你把我們交出去
It wants you to turn us in.
別這麼做
Don’t do it.
他會沒事的
He’s gonna be okay.
求你了 德加
Please, Degas.
求你了
Please.
我們是朋友
We’re friends.
[法語] 蓋布瑞爾……
[in French] Gabriel...
他在哪？
Where is he?
[班吉] 沒有支援 你不該進去
[Benji] You shouldn’t be in there without backup.
[伊森] 班吉 拜託 我們能搞定
[Ethan] Benji, please. We got this.
[班吉] 這簡直是餿主意 放輕鬆啦
[Benji] This is a terrible idea. Just relax.
伊森 這地方到處都是秘密特工
Ethan, this place is crawling with clandestine services.
你該離開那裡
You should get out of there.
我看到他們了 沒事 保持冷靜 班吉
I see them. It’s okay. Stay calm, Benji.
我覺得蓋布瑞爾不會冒危險來參加這個派對
I don’t think Gabriel would risk coming to that party.
撤退
Abort.
不 大家穩住 他在這裡
No, let’s just hold our nerve. He’s here.
他肯定在這裡
He’s got to be here.
伊森 看在上帝的份上 撤退！我們再想辦法
Ethan, for God’s sake, abort! We’ll figure this out.
目前還不成問題
Not a problem yet.
[安保人員] 站著別動
[security] Stay where you are.
別動 亨特
Don’t move, Hunt.
你確定真的是我嗎？
Are you sure it’s really me?
所有單位 我們抓到亨特了 重複 我們抓到亨特了
All units, we have Hunt. I repeat, we have Hunt.
他們聽不見你說話
They can’t hear you.
格蕾絲
Grace.
我甚至都沒看到你是怎麼順走那個的
I didn’t even see you get that one.
優秀的小偷和頂尖的小偷有什麼區別？
What separates a good pickpocket from a great one?
時機
Timing.
兩位先生？
Gentlemen?
動作慢點
Nice and slow.
並非針對個人
Nothing personal.
我說 我挺喜歡你留長髮的
You know, I like the longer hair.
我非常感激你能來 但你不該在這兒
I really appreciate your coming, but you shouldn’t be here.
我沒多少選擇
I didn’t have much choice.
你難道指望我背叛他？
Will you expect me to betray him?
我指望你把他從他自己手裡救出來
I expect you to save him from himself
把世界從他手裡救出來
and the world from him.
基特里奇
Kittridge.
格蕾絲 你這下可惹上天大的麻煩了
You just bought yourself a world of trouble, Grace.
全世界都陷入大麻煩了 伊森
The whole world’s in trouble, Ethan.
你是我唯一信任能救世界的人
You’re the only one I trust to save it.
那麼 下一步怎麼做？
So, what’s the play?
[電擊聲]
[electrical zap]
格蕾絲！
Grace!
[痛苦掙扎] [電擊聲]
[straining] [electrical zap]
格蕾絲
Grace.
蓋布瑞爾派了個任務給你 亨特
Gabriel’s got a job for you, Hunt.
[格蕾絲] 伊森 快醒醒！
[Grace] Ethan, wake up!
[格蕾絲] 好吧 我們該怎麼辦？
[Grace] Okay, what do we do?
告訴我你有計劃
Tell me you have a plan.
他們拿走了我的手錶
They took my watch.
你的手錶？對 還有我的袖釦
Your watch? Yeah, and my cuff links.
裡面有開鎖工具 我明白了
Had lock picks in them. I see.
我們會找到出路的 好嗎？現在 聽著
We’ll find a way out, okay? Now, listen.
啊 太遲了
Ah, it’s too late.
它來了
It’s coming.
好吧 格蕾絲 看著我
Okay, Grace, look at me.
你會挺過去的
You’re gonna get through this.
挺過什麼？
Get through what?
就不斷告訴你自己……
Just keep telling yourself...
這不過是皮肉之痛
it’s only pain.
[擊打聲]
[blow lands]
住手！[蓋布瑞爾] 別碰他！
Stop! [Gabriel] Don’t touch him!
你傷害不了他
You can’t hurt him.
不是那樣
Not that way.
帶你回上海？
Take you back to Shanghai?
她叫什麼名字來著？
What was her name?
朱莉婭！
Julia!
前亨特夫人
The former Mrs. Hunt.
伊森沒跟你提過她嗎？
Did Ethan fail to mention her?
一個叫戴維安的傢伙抓了她……
A fellow named Davian took her...
拿她敲詐索要某種東西
and ransomed her for something
一件只有伊森才能弄到的東西
only Ethan could get.
戴維安稱它為“兔腳”
Davian called it the Rabbit’s Foot.
但它還有另一個名字
But it had another name.
反上帝
The Anti-God.
他們從未告訴過你那個罐子裡裝的是什麼 對吧？
They never told you what was in that canister, did they?
但你心裡一直很好奇
But you always wondered.
偷走“兔腳”只是他一生行為模式中的
Stealing the Rabbit’s Foot was just one event
一次縮影 一次又一次地不斷重演
in a lifelong pattern, repeating itself over and over.
為了拯救他試圖挽救的每一個生命 他拿數百萬人的性命去作賭注
For every life he’s tried to save, he’s gambled millions more,
一次次孤注一擲 不斷加倍押注
doubling down and down again.
而現在 地球上每一個活人的命運
And now the fate of every living soul on Earth is
都是他的責任
his responsibility.
你一定筋疲力盡了吧
You must be exhausted.
鑰匙在哪裡？
Where’s the key?
放了她
Let her go.
然後我們再談 我們時間不夠了
Then we’ll discuss it. We don’t have the time.
今晚你珍視的人中會有人死去
Someone you hold close will die tonight
為了那些你素未謀面的人
for the sake of those you will never meet,
除非你完全按我說的做
unless you do exactly as I say.
他還說過在火車上鑰匙就會是他的 還記得嗎？
He also said the key would be his on the train, remember?
你原本只有一個任務：
You had one job:
上火車 拿到鑰匙 下火車
Get on the train, get the key, get off the train.
[盧瑟] 倘若你把事情搞砸 主子知情後會有何反應？
How did your master take the news when it found out you blew it?
你失敗了
You failed,
現在智體已經拋棄了你
and now the Entity has forsaken you.
你的團隊暴露了 伊森
Your team’s been compromised, Ethan.
我知道盧瑟在幹什麼 我知道你們在計劃什麼
I know what Luther’s doing. I know what you’re planning.
敢反抗我 我會讓你付出慘痛代價
Resist me and I’ll make you pay dearly.
如果你合作
If you cooperate,
我可以幫忙
I can help.
拿什麼來交換？
In exchange for what?
你們在尋找一艘在處女航中失蹤的俄羅斯潛艇
You’re searching for a Russian submarine vanished on its maiden voyage.
[班吉] K-559 塞瓦斯托波爾號
[Benji] The K559 Sevastopol.
[班吉] 一艘能完美避開所有現存聲納的最先進潛艇
A state-of-the-art submarine completely undetectable to any known sonar.
而它隱形的秘密就是那個
And the secret to its invisibility was that.
[盧瑟] 波德科瓦
[Luther] The Podkova.
[班吉] 一個反聲學演算法驅動裝置
[Benji] A counter-acoustic algorithmic drive
位於塞瓦斯托波爾號的聲吶球艙內
located in theSevastopol’s sonar sphere.
在2012年的冬天
Now, in the winter of 2012
俄羅斯人發現了一種來源不明的電腦病毒
the Russians discovered a computer virus of unknown origin
正悄然侵蚀著他們的黑海艦隊
spreading through their Black Sea fleet.
一個數字秘密特工
A digital covert operative.
我們懷疑這種神秘病毒原本只是打算
We suspect this mystery virus was only intended
破壞“波德科瓦” 讓潛艇能被探測到
to sabotage the Podkova, rendering the submarine detectable.
結果……它誘騙船員
Instead... It tricked the crew
擊沉了他們自己
into sinking themselves.
[俄羅斯軍官] 艦長！我們自己的魚雷沒有回應
[Russian officer] Captain! Our own torpedo is not responding.
它正衝著我們來！
It’s coming right at us!
我們的魚雷在自動制導！距離400米！
Our torpedo’s homing! Range 400 meters!
拉響碰撞警——
Sound the collision alar--
[盧瑟] 如果我們沒猜錯 消滅智體所需的核心東西
[Luther] If we’re right, the one thing we need to kill the Entity,
它的原始碼
its original source code,
就埋在塞瓦斯托波爾號的聲吶球艙裡
is buried in theSevastopol’s sonar sphere.
[班吉] 就在海洋深處的底端 被時間凍結
[Benji] Somewhere deep at the bottom of the ocean, frozen in time,
連智體都觸及不到的地方
where even the Entity can’t reach it.
現在 “波德科瓦”的外殼被設計成強行拆卸即自毀
Now, the Podkova’s housing was designed to self-destruct if tampered with.
唯一能安全開啟它的方法……
The only way to safely open it...
就是使用特製的十字形鑰匙
is with a specially designed cruciform key.
[盧瑟] 兩半鑰匙分別由塞瓦斯托波爾號的艦長和副艦長持有
[Luther] The two halves of which were held by the Sevastopol’s captain and XO.
[蓋布瑞爾] 他們是從漂流的浮冰中
[Gabriel] They were pulled from the drifting pack ice
2012年的春季
in the spring of 2012
被因紐特漁民撈出來的
by Inuit fishermen.
以你的能力
A man of your skills
現在已經擁有了將那艘潛艇精確定位到方圓幾碼內的一切條件
now has all he needs to pinpoint that sub down to the square yard.
你以為我會去弄到原始碼然後帶給你
You think I’m gonna get the source code and bring it to you.
我不是以為 我知道你會
I don’t think. I know.
我會放你走
I’m gonna let you go.
然後你會找到智體的原始碼並帶給我
Then you’re gonna find the Entity’s source code and bring it to me
用來交換格蕾絲
in exchange for Grace.
然後我會接管對智體的控制權
Then I’ll take control of the Entity,
就是那個被你放出來的神燈精靈
the proverbial genie you let out.
“兔腳”
The Rabbit’s Foot.
反上帝
The Anti-God.
[蓋布瑞爾] 那可不是什麼生化武器——
[Gabriel] It wasn’t a biological or a chemical weapon
你從上海拿走的東西
you took from Shanghai.
你用來交換朱莉婭的小藥瓶裡裝的是惡意程式碼
The vial you traded for Julia contained malicious code.
那宛如洪荒時期的數位原漿
The primordial digital ooze
武器正是從中演化而來的
from which a weapon evolved.
一種東方國家無法使其奏效的武器
A weapon the East couldn’t make work.
一種西方靠自己可能永遠也製造不出的武器
A weapon the West might never have made on their own.
你當時不知道自己偷的是什麼
You didn’t know what you were stealing.
我們誰也不知道
None of us did.
我知道我為什麼要偷它
I knew why I was stealing it.
他們綁架了我的妻子
They kidnapped my wife.
偷走“兔腳”是我救回她的唯一方法
Stealing the Rabbit’s Foot was the only way I could get her back.
我擊沉那艘潛艇的責任和智體一樣大
I sank that submarine as much as the Entity did.
伊森 如果沒有你
Without you, Ethan,
就不會有智體
there’d be no Entity.
要是你在接下來的幾天裡找不到那艘潛艇……
And if you don’t find that sub in the next few days...
我們所熟知的那個世界就要終結了
It’s the end of the world as we know it.
而這一切都將歸咎於他
And it will all be his fault.
他自己心裡清楚
He knows it.
看著我
Look at me.
告訴我 我說錯了嗎？
Tell me I’m wrong.
[伊森] 假牙
[Ethan] False tooth.
氰化鉀膠囊
Cyanide capsule.
我只要咬下去 六十秒內就會死掉
I bite down on this, and I’m dead in sixty seconds.
你就永遠別想拿到原始碼
You’ll never see that source code.
別碰他！
Don’t touch him!
吐出來
Spit it out.
先放了她
Release her first.
你不會這麼做的
You won’t do it.
我已經沒什麼可失去的了
I got nothing to lose.
但格蕾絲有
But Grace does.
要是你死了
And with you dead,
誰來救她？
who’s gonna save her?
吐出來 伊森
Spit it out. Ethan.
記住 格蕾絲 這只不過是疼痛罷了
Remember, Grace, it’s only pain.
醫護人員！伊森！
Medic!Ethan!
[醫護人員] 拿除顫儀來！
[medic] Bring the defibrillator!
快點！
Come on!
等等 等等！充電中
Wait, wait! Charging.
充電中
Charging.
準備就緒
Ready.
[伊森] 鑰匙！
[Ethan] Keys!
[蓋布瑞爾] 我要他活著
[Gabriel] I need him alive.
殺了她
Kill her.
蓋布瑞爾要逃走了
Gabriel’s getting away.
快去
Go.
[槍聲]
[gunfire]
[玻璃破碎聲]
[glass breaks]
[格蕾絲] 伊森！
[Grace] Ethan!
[拳腳相交聲]
[blows landing]
[悶哼與呼喊聲持續]
[grunting, yelling continues]
[擊打聲]
[blows landing]
[金屬碰撞聲]
[metallic clank]
你沒事吧？
You okay?
蓋布瑞爾要逃走了
Gabriel’s getting away.
格蕾絲
Grace.
喔 等等
Whoa. Hey.
你該不會以為我會讓他們……
You don’t think that I would have let them...
格蕾絲 我絕不會讓你出任何事的
Grace, I would never let anything happen to you.
沒多嚴重
Nothing serious.
我是說——
I mean--
什——
Wha--
我是說——
I mean--
這個嘛 他們剛才要殺了你
Well, they were gonna kill you.
對 對
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊 沒錯
嘿 順便說一句 你剛才幹得太棒了
Hey, you did great, by the way.
我們真得走了
We really got to go.
[《不可能的任務》主題曲響起]
[ Mission: Impossible theme playing]
不許動！
Freeze!
我抓住他了！
I got him!
我們討論過這個 伊森要他活口
We talked about this. Ethan wants him alive.
[法語] 我要他死
[in French] I want him dead.
她早晚會要了我的命
She’ll be the death of me.
伊森
Ethan.
[伊森 法語] 怎麼了？
[Ethan in French] What is it?
這就是他同它對話的方式
It’s how he spoke to it.
你該不會真打算……？
You’re not seriously gonna...?
[法語] 這會徹頭徹尾地改變你
[in French] It will change you.
好吧 我在這
All right, I’m here.
現在你想怎麼樣？
Now what do you want?
[低沉的聲音] 晚上好 亨特先生
[deep voice] Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
你有疑問
You have questions.
智體有答案
The Entity has answers.
但你必須放它進來
But you have to let it in.
[電擊滋滋聲]
[electrical zapping]
[低沉的聲音] 你知道這個地方
[deep voice] You know this place.
只有反抗才會帶來痛苦
There is only pain if you resist.
[電擊滋滋聲]
[electrical zapping]
再說一次
Again,
你知道這個地方
you know this place.
[伊森] 末日地堡
[Ethan] The Doomsday Vault.
南非
South Africa.
你會在那裡見到智體
You will meet the Entity there.
你會放它進來
You will let it in.
而所有生靈的命運都將在
And the fate of every living thing will be decided
眨眼之間決定
in the blink of an eye.
這是你的使命 你的宿命
This is your calling, your destiny.
[伊森] 我不接受
[Ethan] I don’t accept that.
[電擊滋滋聲]
[electrical zapping]
[低沉的聲音] 在這裡 你沒有任何秘密
[deep voice] In here, you have no secrets.
[電擊滋滋聲]
[electrical zapping]
[班吉] K-559 塞瓦斯托波爾號
[Benji] The K559Sevastopol.
[盧瑟] 波德科瓦
[Luther] The Podkova.
[班吉] 一把十字形鑰匙
[Benji] A cruciform key.
[盧瑟] 我的畢生傑作
[Luther] My magnum opus.
那個驅動器上的演算法
The algorithm on that drive,
當與智體的原始碼配對時
when paired with the Entity’s source code,
將作為你所要求的毒藥膠囊
will act as the poison pill you asked for.
[低沉的聲音] 你計劃從塞瓦斯托波爾號上取回“波德科瓦”
[deep voice] You plan to retrieve the Podkova from theSevastopol
並摧毀智體
and destroy the Entity.
[伊森] 這讓你害怕了
[Ethan] And that scares you.
[低沉的聲音] 智體看到了無限的可能
[deep voice] The Entity sees infinite possibilities.
取回“波德科瓦”
Retrieve the Podkova
你就會冒失去一切的風險
and you risk everything.
[無聲對話]
[no audible dialogue]
[低沉的聲音] 你要去末日地堡
[deep voice] You will go to the Doomsday Vault
放智體進來
and let the Entity in.
這是命中註定的
It is written.
[伊森] 絕不可能
[Ethan] Never.
[低沉的聲音] 終局即將來臨 伊森
[deep voice] The end is coming, Ethan.
你心裡一直都很清楚
You have always known this.
智體為未來帶來了希望
The Entity offers hope for the future.
倖存下來的少數人會變得更加強大
The few who survive will be stronger.
原子之子將從廢墟中崛起
The children of the atom shall rise from the ashes.
而智體將幫助他們重建
And the Entity will help them rebuild.
[英語] 但前提是你得放它進來
[in English] But only if you let it in.
[伊森] 要是我不呢……又會怎樣？
[Ethan] And if I don’t... what then?
毀滅世界 你也只不過是毀滅你自己
Destroy the world and you just destroy yourself.
[低沉的聲音] 抉擇權在你手上
[deep voice] The choice is yours.
擁有智體的未來
The Entity’s future
或者是根本沒有未來
or no future at all.
[伊森] 讓世界被奴役
[Ethan] Let the world be enslaved
還是讓世界被毀滅
or let the world be destroyed.
[低沉的聲音] 現在你才是天選之子
[deep voice] Now you are the chosen one.
蓋布瑞爾是被棄者
Gabriel is outcast.
他已經採取行動試圖接管智體 如你所見
He has taken steps to gain control of the Entity, as you will see.
[蓋布瑞爾] 敢反抗我 我會讓你付出慘痛代價
[Gabriel] Resist me and I’ll make you pay dearly.
今晚你珍視的人中會有人死去
Someone you hold close will die tonight.
[伊森] 盧瑟
[Ethan] Luther.
[低沉的聲音] 你知道人類必須做什麼才能改變他們的命運
[deep voice] You know what humanity must do to change their destiny.
你知道他們無法阻止必然發生的事
You know they cannot stop the inevitable.
他們會以為自己別無選擇 從而走向自我毀滅
They will destroy themselves believing they have no choice.
他們的終局到了
Their time has come.
在四天之內
In four days,
他們將面臨最終的裁決
they will face their final reckoning.
[無聲對話]
[no audible dialogue]
[聲音含糊] 這是真的嗎？這是真的嗎？
[muffled] Is this real? Is this real?
是的
Yeah.
你是真的嗎？你是真的
Are you real? You’re real.
你是真的 對
You’re real. Yeah.
它知道了 [班吉] 它知道什麼了？
It knows. [Benji] It knows what?
我需要一支筆 能寫字的東西
I need a pen. Something to write on.
你帶著團隊 帶著他們往北走
You’ll take the team. You’ll take them north.
[班吉] 北邊？往北去哪？
[Benji] North? North where?
塞瓦斯托波爾號 塞瓦斯托波爾號？
The Sevastopol. The Sevastopol?
我必須被抓 這是我能去那裡的唯一方法
I have to get caught. It’s the only way I could get there.
甚高頻接收機 減壓艙
VHF receiver. Decompression chamber.
偷一架飛機 一架舊飛機 沒有應答機 沒有GPS
Steal a plane. An old plane. No transponder, no GPS.
這一切全都是模擬訊號
Everything is analog.
一架 DC-3 飛機
A DC-3.
你需要的一切都在這裡面了
Everything you need is right in there.
記得每兩小時傳送一次座標 持續15分鐘
Remember to transmit the coordinates every two hours for 15 minutes
能聽的時候我會聽的
and I’ll listen when I can.
現在你是隊長了 不 我——
You’re team leader now. No, I--
班吉 照顧好你的團隊
Benj, take care of your team.
鑰匙
Key.
你離冰面遠點 什麼冰面？
You stay off the ice. What ice?
求你了 無論你做什麼 不管發生什麼 離冰面遠點
Just please, whatever you do, no matter what, stay off the ice.
好 好 行
Okay. Okay. Yeah.
快走
Go.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
盧瑟
Luther.
[蓋布瑞爾] 告訴伊森……
[Gabriel] Tell Ethan...
我會等他
I’ll be waiting for him.
嘿 盧瑟
Hey, Luther.
嘿 伊森
Hey, Ethan.
和蓋布瑞爾進展得怎麼樣？
How’d it go with Gabriel?
嗯 挺順利的 我們……
Yeah, it went well. We...
是嗎
You don’t say.
那麼 那血是誰的？
And so, whose blood is that?
什麼？
What?
噢 不是我們認識的人
Oh, it’s no one we know.
那是我心裡想的那個東西嗎？沒什麼特別的
Is that what I think it is? Nothing special.
鈽彈芯
Plutonium core.
我估計威力大概有五、六百萬噸當量
I’m guessing a five or six megaton yield.
足以把整座城市變成玻璃菸灰缸
Enough to turn this entire city into a glass ashtray.
那可……
That’s...
不太妙
not good.
[金屬撞擊聲]
[metal clanks]
已經試過了 開不了
Already tried. Can’t open it.
我看到了
I see that.
蓋布瑞爾拿到了毒藥膠囊
Gabriel has the poison pill.
你可能得去找到他
You might want to find him.
嗯 我們會找到的 你能拆除這玩意嗎？
Yeah, we will. Can you disarm that?
我只需要阻止這九個引爆器引發彈芯內爆
I just have to stop these nine detonators from imploding the core.
拆掉一個引爆器 就不會內爆
Detach one detonator, no implosion.
沒有內爆 就沒有臨界質量
And no implosion, no critical mass.
沒有臨界質量 就不會有六百萬噸的大爆炸
And no critical mass, no six megaton blast.
我們還有多少時間？足夠你逃離這兒的時間
How much time we have? Enough time for you to get out of here.
也許用那些工具我能拆掉這些合頁
Maybe with those tools I get these hinges off.
就算你能把那扇鐵門弄開
Even if you could get that gate open,
我還是得拆掉一個引爆器
I still have to detach one detonator.
你這是什麼意思？
What are you saying?
我能保住這座城市……
I can save the city...
但這整個地下隧道網將會坍塌
but this entire network of tunnels is going to cave in.
無論誰去拆掉那個引爆器……
Whoever detaches that detonator...
都必死無疑
is going to die.
我們倆都站在那扇門的這一邊
We’re both on the right side of that gate
你心裡清楚
and you know it.
盧瑟 把工具包扔給我
Luther, throw me the tool bag.
它們放在這絕非偶然 伊森 你知道為什麼
They weren’t left here by accident, Ethan. You know why.
蓋布瑞爾需要我活著
Gabriel needs me alive.
而他需要你死
And he needs you to die.
因為你是唯一能再製造出一顆毒藥膠囊的人
Because you are the only one who can make another poison pill.
而我是唯一能趕到那艘潛艇上的人
And I am the only one who can get to that submarine.
[蓋布瑞爾] 告訴伊森……
[Gabriel] Tell Ethan...
我會等他
I’ll be waiting for him.
[伊森] 如果他拿到了毒藥膠囊
[Ethan] If he has the poison pill,
我就必須把“波德科瓦”帶給他
I have to bring him the Podkova
這樣他才能控制智體
so he can control the Entity.
就在這裡道別吧
This is where you leave me.
盧瑟
Luther.
[盧瑟] 不然我們還能幹嘛？
[Luther] What are we gonna do?
退休？
Retire?
去釣魚？
Go fishing?
這是我的任務
This is my mission.
我生來就是為了完成使命的
This is what I was born to do.
盧瑟 我做不到 我做不到
Luther, I can’t. I can’t.
兄弟 你什麼都不用說
There’s nothing you need to say, brother.
我懂
I know.
我正安於我該在的地方
I’m right where I want to be.
伊森……你得抓緊時間了
Ethan... you need to hurry.
你快走
You go.
找到蓋布瑞爾
Find Gabriel.
阻止他
Stop him.
為了我們素未謀面的人
For those we never meet.
加布瑞爾 你這個混蛋
Gabriel, you son of a bitch,
在菲尼亞斯·弗裡克面前 無人能夠倖免
no one is safe from Phineas Phreak.
[無聲對話]
[no audible dialogue]
[布里格斯] 德加斯 我這邊的人
[Briggs] My man Degas.
他死了嗎？
Is he dead?
不 他——他活著
No, he’s-- he’s alive.
布里格斯 對吧？
Briggs, isn’t it?
但這不是你的真名
But that isn’t your real name.
那又怎樣？
What of it?
你的真名是吉姆·菲爾普斯
Your real name is Jim Phelps.
和你父親一樣
Like your father.
他曾經也在情報局服役
He was in the service, too.
你七歲那年他失蹤了
He vanished when you were seven.
你參軍是為了查明他到底出了什麼事
You joined to find out what happened to him,
結果你發現他惹上了官司
and you found out he had legal trouble.
當時他面臨著抉擇：
He was offered the choice:
加入不可能任務情報局……
To join the IMF...
還是在監獄裡度過餘生
or spend the rest of his life in prison.
就像你一樣 亨特
Just like you, Hunt.
不過在你這兒 罪名好像是謀殺
Only in your case, the charge was murder, I believe.
但讓我猜猜看
But let me guess.
你是被陷害的
You were framed.
就像你多年前在布拉格聲稱自己被陷害一樣
Just like your claim you were framed all those years ago in Prague.
那次任務是怎麼搞砸的
How the mission went sideways.
你是怎麼失去整個團隊的
How you lost your whole team.
在你的版本里 我父親成了叛徒
Your story had my father down as a traitor.
這就是你殺了他的原因
That’s why you killed him.
這是真的 我也希望事實並非如此
It’s true. I wish it weren’t.
你以為我念念不忘？
You think I’m carrying that?
我追來這兒是為了復仇？
That I’m here for revenge?
或者……什麼？
Or... what?
為了洗清我父親的名聲？
To clear my father’s name?
這是我現在的名字了
It’s my name now.
不
No.
我在這兒
I’m here
是因為我知道你就是那個
because I know you’re the reason
讓全世界陷入末日危機邊緣的原因
the world’s staring down the barrel at Armageddon.
我也知道這已經不是第一次了
And I also know it’s not the first time
你拿全人類的命運去下賭注
you’ve gambled with the fate of the human race.
這一切對我來說都無所謂……
And none of that would matter to me...
如果你哪怕有一次
if you’d ever once
是在聽從
been following
指揮
orders.
布里格斯
Briggs.
菲爾普斯
Phelps.
吉姆
Jim.
智體想讓你恨我
The Entity wants you to hate me.
它就指望著這一點
It’s counting on it.
擊敗它的唯一方法就是做那件
And the only way to beat it is to do the one thing
它絕對意料不到的事
it would never expect us to do.
那是什麼？
What’s that?
你忘了我很瞭解你 亨特
You forget I know you, Hunt.
我深知你所有不可能任務情報局的心理戰術
I know all your IMF mind games.
等這一切結束 等他們把你榨乾利用完
When this is over, when they’re done with you,
你和我
you and me,
我們倆會有個清算
we’ll have our reckoning.
你的朋友真是可惜了
It’s a shame about your friend.
不過話又說回來
Then again,
習慣失去了他們 你早就習以為常了
you’re used to losing them.
長官？
Sir?
[基特里奇] 就在你執行你自己私人的外勤行動時
[Kittridge] While you’ve been out conducting your own personal field operation,
智體已經滲透到了印度、
the Entity has infiltrated the nuclear command centers of India,
以色列、巴基斯坦和朝鮮的核指揮中心
Israel, Pakistan, and North Korea.
今天世界標準時間0400時
Today at 0400 hours Zulu time,
法國拉姆西斯基地被攻破
France’s RAMSES facility was breached.
他們的全部核武庫現在都處於智體的指揮和控制之下
Their entire nuclear arsenal is now under the Entity’s command and control.
這就只剩下四個國家擁有安全的核武庫了
That leaves only four nations with secure nuclear arsenals.
英國、中國、俄羅斯還有我們
U.K., China, Russia and us.
曾經的你
Everything you were,
你所做過的一切
everything you’ve done
都是為了走到這一步
has come to this.
中情局黑庫入侵案
The CIA Black Vault break-in.
抱歉 什麼是“NOC名單”？
I’m sorry, what is a "NOC list"?
我們海外秘密特工的完整檔案記錄
A complete record of our covert operatives overseas.
這麼說 這就是那個——
So this is the man who--
入侵我們自己黑庫的人
Broke into our own Black Vault
順走了我們自家間諜的名單 沒錯
and stole the list of our own spies, yes.
但他後來把名單歸還了
He did return the list.
在下一頁寫著呢
It’s on the next page.
我沒看錯吧？克里姆林宮爆炸案？
Am I reading this correctly? The Kremlin bombing?
說句公道話 那枚炸彈原本就是為了除掉他
In fairness, the bomb was actually meant to kill him.
他在國家情報局的安保簡報會上
He gassed a security briefing
在國家情報局
at the National Intelligence Directorate.
[西德尼] 那不過是兩個月前的事
[Sidney] That was just two months ago.
當時你們二位應該都在那個會議現場
You two would have been in that meeting.
他是以基特里奇先生助手身份入場的
He arrived in the form of Mister Kittridge’s aide.
並且據我所知 是以基特里奇先生的身份離開的
And left as Mister Kittridge, I believe.
[瑟林] 這就能解釋手銬是怎麼回事了
[Serling] This explains the handcuffs.
但他為什麼會在這兒 依然沒有說清楚
It’s still not clear why he’s here.
不管你喜不喜歡 眼前這個男人是我們最後的退路
Like it or not, what we’re looking at is our means of last resort.
極有可能是我們避免核末日危機的唯一希望
Quite possibly our only hope of averting nuclear Armageddon.
如果我們想控制智體
If we want to control the Entity,
就必須跟他打交道
we have to deal with him.
倘若他願意接受
Should he choose to accept.
特工亨特
Agent Hunt.
總統女士 對於您的不幸遭遇 我深表遺憾
Madam President. I’m sorry for your loss.
請坐
Please sit.
講講看
Let’s hear it.
我需要那把鑰匙以及一艘艦艇的使用權
I need that key and the use of a ship.
具體來說 是一艘航空母艦
Specifically, an aircraft carrier.
準確地講 是喬治·H·W·布什號
More specifically, the George H.W. Bush.
他想要“使用”
He wants the "use of"
價值六十五億美元的核動力軍事資產
a six-and-a-half billion dollar nuclear-powered military asset.
還要指示艦長全力配合我的每一個要求
With instructions for the ship’s commander to accommodate my every request.
究竟要去做什麼？
To do what exactly?
利用那把鑰匙以及它能開啟的東西
Use that key and what it opens
去消滅智體
to kill the Entity.
消滅智體就意味著網路世界的徹底毀滅
Killing the Entity means the annihilation of cyberspace.
其帶來的後果將是災難性的
The consequences of which are catastrophic.
我憑什麼要按你說的做？
Why the hell would I do what you suggest?
恕我直言 總統女士 您別無選擇
Respectfully, Madam President, you have no other choice.
永遠都有別的選擇 不 女士
There is always another choice. No, ma’am.
在這種情況下 可沒有好選擇
In this case, not a good one.
全球的核大國都陷入了人人自危的惡性迴圈
The world’s nuclear powers are in a paranoid downward spiral.
每個國家本都有機會把他們的導彈下線
Every nation had a chance to take their missiles offline,
但誰也不信任別人會這麼做
but no one trusted anyone else to do that.
國務院正在向您發出警告 外交渠道正在癱瘓崩潰
Your State Department is warning you that diplomatic channels are breaking down.
每一個手頭還掌控著核武庫的人 都在考慮先發制人
Everyone who still has control of their arsenals is considering a first strike.
就跟您現在想的一樣
Just like you are.
情報界心知肚明
The intelligence community knows
智體在邊幹邊學
that the Entity is learning as it goes.
它變得越來越聰明 越來越強大
It’s getting smarter, it’s getting stronger.
他們很清楚我們只有72小時
They know that we have only 72 hours
趕在地球上所有其他核武庫落入智體的控制之前
before every other nuclear arsenal on Earth is under the Entity’s control.
三天後 它會把全部能量集中於
Three days before it focuses the full force of its energy
在這顆星球上最堅固、最安全的防禦系統上：我們的系統
on the toughest, most secure defense system on the planet: Ours.
到那個時候 國防部將別無選擇 只能堅決主張
At which point, the Defense Department will have no choice but to insist
屆時你得去開啟那個箱子
that you open that case,
輸入程式碼 向世上其餘八個核武庫
enter the codes, and launch an all-out preemptive strike
發起全面先發制人的打擊
on the world’s eight other nuclear arsenals
搶在智體接管我們的核武庫之前
before the Entity takes control of ours.
總統女士
Madam President,
要麼由您來毀滅世界 要麼由智體來毀滅
either you destroy the world or the Entity does.
無論哪種情況 都是死局
In any case, it is checkmate.
[埃裡卡] 還有另一個選擇
[Erika] There is another choice.
你可以告訴我關於那把鑰匙你知道的一切
You could tell me what you know about that key
把控制智體的力量交給我們
and give us the power to control the Entity.
總統女士 如果我相信那是真的 我會把我知道的全部告訴你
Madam President, if I believed that were true, I would tell you everything I know.
全部！
Everything!
您曾掌管中情局 您一眼就能看出什麼是心理戰
You ran the CIA, you know psychological warfare when you see it.
看看周圍吧
Just look around.
我們正身處智體塑造的現實中
We are in the Entity’s reality.
而我相信 它正指望著由您來阻止我
And I believe it’s counting on you to stop me.
如果你說的是真的
If what you’re saying is true,
你怎麼能確定智體不正是想讓我們去實施
how can you be sure the Entity doesn’t want us to do
你現在提議的方案呢？
exactly what you’re proposing right now?
[伊森] 因為它知道您絕不會做這麼違背常理的事
[Ethan] Because it knows you would never do anything so illogical.
知道信任我簡直是瘋了
That you would be insane to trust me.
而這也恰恰是您應該信任我的原因
And that is precisely why you should.
就這一次
For once,
讓我們給智體個難題 讓它去操心我們下一步要幹什麼吧
let’s let the Entity worry about what we’re going to do.
總統女士 我是在擔心另外那三個國家
I’m worried about those three other nations, Madam President,
那些仍然掌控著自己核武庫的國家
still in control of their arsenals.
那些國家可能會陷入恐慌並發動全面攻擊
Nations who could panic and launch a full-scale attack
而他卻在外面帶著一艘航空母艦 做著鬼才知道的事！
while he’s out there with an aircraft carrier, doing God knows what!
而他卻在外面試圖去消滅智體
While he’s out there trying to kill the Entity.
我們大家都很清楚這是個極其糟糕的主意
Which we all know is a terrible idea.
總統女士 求您了 我請求給我三天時間 在此期間由您
Madam President, please. I’m asking for three days while you
來維持局勢平靜
keep the world calm.
三天
Three days.
我曾經……
Have I ever...
讓您失望過嗎？
let you down before?
要是智體決定在這之前就發起攻擊呢？
And when the Entity decides to attack before then?
它手頭的導彈已經足夠殺死數十億人了 它為什麼還沒動手？
It has enough missiles to kill billions already. Why hasn’t it done it?
因為它是一臺機器
Because it’s a machine.
它在像機器一樣思考 不 它的思考模式……
It’s thinking like a machine. No, its thinking...
[國家安全局代表] 它的思考方式非0即1
[NSA representative] Its thinking is binary.
……是由它從我們身上學到的東西決定的
...is dictated by what it’s learned from us.
它之所以還沒發動攻擊 是因為它還沒有取得絕對控制
It hasn’t launched because it doesn’t have total control.
它需要全世界的全部核武庫來確保達成理想的結果：
It needs the world’s entire atomic arsenal to guarantee the desired outcome:
人類的徹底毀滅
The total annihilation of humankind.
總統女士
Madam President,
它一定會等待的
it is going to wait.
[埃裡卡] 倫敦諾斯伍德核行動與目標定位中心已被攻破
[Erika] Northwood Nuclear Operations and Targeting Centre in London has been breached.
英國已經失去了對其核武庫的控制
The United Kingdom has lost control of its arsenal.
我最後再問你一次
I will ask you one last time.
這能解鎖什麼？
What does this unlock?
埃裡卡
Erika,
我需要你信任我
I need you to trust me
最後一次
one last time.
相信我跟你說的：
Trust me when I tell you:
當倒計時在72小時後結束時
When that clock runs out in 72 hours,
我會按下那個按鈕
I will press that button,
而那將是你的責任
and that will be your responsibility.
總統女士——
Madam President--
警衛
Sergeants,
把他關起來！
lock him up!
[士兵] 你聽到總統說的了
[soldier] You heard the President.
你有72小時
You have 72 hours.
她說等時機到了 你自然會知道怎麼用這玩意的
She says you’ll know what to do with this when the time comes.
長官！
Sir!
祝你好運
Good luck.
等這一切結束後 我在上面給你留了條留言
I left you a message on there for when this is over.
[伊森] 你可以親口告訴我……
[Ethan] You can tell me yourself...
之後
after.
當他們給我們做出選擇時 他們讓我們立下了誓言
They made us take an oath when they gave us the choice.
我們在陰影中生死
We live and die in the shadows
為了我們珍視的人……
for those we hold close...
也為了我們素未謀面的人
and for those we never meet.
我知道你在想什麼
I know what’s on your mind.
當你留著那把鑰匙時 你就做出了正確的決定
You did the right thing when you kept the key.
兄弟 你永遠都在正義的一方
You’ve always been on the right side, brother.
永遠
Always.
切記
Never forget,
我們的生命不由單一行為來定義
our lives are not defined by any one action.
我們的生命
Our lives
是我們所有選擇的總和
are the sum of our choices.
我無怨無悔
I have no regrets.
你也不該有
Neither should you.
[尼利] 埃裡卡——
[Neely] Did Erika--
總統是否有對你說過
Did the President
有沒有告訴你這紙條背後的寓意？
tell you the meaning behind this note?
沒有 女士
No, ma’am.
塞爾維亞 1996年5月22日 我們倆都失去了至親至愛的人
Serbia. May 22nd, 1996. We both lost someone we loved.
確實如此
Very much.
全因掌權者無一人膽敢承擔風險
All because no one in authority would take a risk.
先生 我正坐在一桶火藥上呢
I’m sitting on a powder keg, mister.
就在那個地平線之外 停著俄羅斯唯一的航母庫茲涅佐夫海軍元帥號
Just over that horizon is Russia’s only aircraft carrier, the Admiral Kuznetsov.
只要一步走錯 就會引發二戰以來
I am one wrong move away from the first shoot-out
兩艘平頂船之間的首次交火
between two flattops since World War II.
稍有不慎就會引爆第三次世界大戰
One flinch from touching off World War III.
而你現在卻要我直接把你送進暴風眼去
And you’re asking me to fly you directly into the eye of the storm.
是的 女士 正是如此
Yes, ma’am, I am.
你到底要找什麼？
What exactly are you looking for?
[班吉] SOSUS
[Benji] SOSUS.
是“水下聲學監聽系統”的縮寫
Short for "Sound Surveillance System."
那是一套可以追溯到冷戰時期的全球水下聲學纜線網路
It’s a worldwide network of undersea acoustic cables
追溯到冷戰時期
dating back to the Cold War.
如果世界上任何地方發生了任何有一定規模的水下事件
If an undersea event of any significance happens anywhere in the world,
這些監聽站中的某一個就能將該事件精確定位到平方米以內
one of these listening stations will pinpoint that event to the square meter.
[伊森] 而這些SOSUS監聽站中的某一個
[Ethan] And one of these SOSUS stations
定會記錄下我們失蹤的那艘俄羅斯潛艇
will have recorded our missing Russian submarine’s
在2012年冬天撞擊海底的聲音
impact on the sea floor in the winter of 2012.
卻根本不明白這一事件的重大意義
Without ever understanding the significance of the event.
[班吉] 況且俄羅斯人清楚塞瓦斯托波爾號是什麼時候失聯的
[Benji] Whereas the Russians know when the Sevastopolvanished.
他們只是不確定具體的地點
They’re just not exactly sure where.
[法語] 我們必須做出抉擇
[In French] We must make a choice.
究竟是哪一個
Which one
在所有這些SOSUS監聽站中捕獲到了那一事件？
out of all these SOSUS stations picked up the event?
我們知道塞瓦斯托波爾號船員的遺體是在海冰中被打撈出來的
We know the bodies of the Sevastopol’screw were recovered in sea ice.
既然是由因紐特漁民打撈上來的……
And since they were recovered by Inuit fishermen...
我們推測它是在北極某處沉沒的
We’re guessing it went down somewhere in the Arctic.
搜尋面積大約為五百五十萬平方英里
A search area of roughly five and a half million square miles.
意味著最有可能記錄下它的SOSUS監聽站是……
Meaning the most likely SOSUS station to pick it up is...
這一個 在白令海
This one. In the Bering Sea.
[伊森] 聖馬修島
[Ethan] St. Matthew Island.
俄羅斯人也會知道這一點
The Russians will know this.
他們為什麼不乾脆強攻該島呢？
Why haven’t they just stormed the island already?
因為聖馬修島是美國政府的設施
Because St. Matthew is a U.S. Government installation.
明目張膽的侵略行為會引發第三次世界大戰
An overt act of aggression would trigger World War III.
但現在末日要來了
But now Armageddon is coming.
[法語] 俄方現在已經豁出去了
[in French] And the Russians have nothing to lose.
你的夥伴們清楚他們正深陷重圍嗎？
Do your friends know they’re walking into a potential siege?
他們知道這是職責所在
They know that’s the job.
因此 為了從塞瓦斯托波爾號上找回智體的原始碼
So, to retrieve the Entity’s source code from Sevastopol,
伊森需要聖馬修島上的精確座標
Ethan needs the precise coordinates from St. Matthew Island.
顯然還得有一艘潛艇
And a submarine, obviously.
一艘願意把你送去任何地方的潛艇
One that’s willing to take you where you want to go.
絕不多問
No questions asked.
女士
Ma’am.
前提是
And that’s assuming
你的同伴真能拿到座標
your friends can actually get the coordinates.
預計我們得每隔兩小時發送十五分鐘……
Which we’re expected to transmit for fifteen minutes every two hours...
指望伊森能設法收到我們的訊號
In the hope that Ethan is somehow able to receive our signal.
你打算怎麼從冰蓋下面浮上來？
How do you intend to make it out from under the ice cap?
將座標發給我之後 我的隊員會前往該處
After sending me the coordinates, my team will make their way there.
[班吉] 接著 伊森會攜帶一臺甚高頻發射器
[Benji] Now, Ethan will have a VHF transmitter
這樣我們在冰層下方就能鎖定他的精確方位
which will enable us to zero in on his exact location under the ice.
到時候我們只要拿上一把電鋸然後——
All we have to do then is grab a chainsaw and--
什麼？在冰蓋上鋸個洞直接把伊森拽出來？
What? Cut a hole in the ice cap and just pull Ethan out?
等一下 這得看那艘沉船有多深
Hang on. Depending on how deep that wreck is,
伊森浮出水面前就會患上嚴重的減壓病
Ethan will have severe decompression sickness before he reaches the surface.
這也就是我們帶上這玩意的緣故
Which is why we have this.
[格蕾絲] 那究竟是個什麼東西？
[Grace] What the hell is that?
這是一套最先進的可充氣式高壓減壓艙
This is a state-of-the-art inflatable hyperbaric decompression chamber.
你在開玩笑吧
You’re not serious.
什麼？你是說伊森的命
What? You mean to tell me that Ethan’s life
以及地球上所有生命的命運
and the fate of all life on Earth
全看我們所有人能否在分毫不差的同一地點碰頭
depends on us all meeting at the exact same place
且在完全相同的時刻碰頭
at the exact same time,
就在白令海冰封的某個角落……
somewhere in the frozen Bering Sea...
方能成事
with that.
[班吉] 沒錯
[Benji] Exactly.
那如果我們在趕到之前他就淹死了呢？
And what if he drowns before we get there?
大機率會的
In all likelihood, he will.
但在那麼冷的水裡 低體溫症會減緩他的新陳代謝
But in water that cold, the hypothermia will slow down his metabolic functions
併為我們爭取時間復甦他
and buy us time to revive him.
這就是你的計劃？
That’s your plan?
沒錯
Exactly.
這就是我們的計劃
That’s our plan.
射程內唯一的潛艇是“俄亥俄號”
The only submarine in range is the Ohio.
傑克·布萊德索的艇
Jack Bledsoe’s boat.
在水下潛航時
When submerged,
只能透過超低頻電臺聯絡他——遮蔽任何數字傳輸
he’s reachable only by VLF radio-- shielded from any digital transmission.
這意味著他對這東西免疫
That means he is immune to this thing.
但前提是他必須保持潛航
But only if he stays submerged.
“魚鷹”能在兩小時內把你送過去 但燃料不夠等待
An Osprey can get you there in two hours, but it won’t have enough fuel to wait.
別無選擇
There’s no other choice.
如果布萊德索收到我的命令
If Bledsoe receives my command,
如果他相信這是真的
if he believes it to be authentic,
他可能會上浮到潛望鏡深度
he might come to periscope depth.
他可能會等三十秒
He might wait thirty seconds.
如果你們哪怕遲到了一分鐘……
If you are even one minute late...
給我這個機會就行
Just give me this chance.
[國家偵察局代表] 你放走亨特了？
[NRO representative] You let Hunt go?
我是這麼說的 帶著鑰匙？
That’s what I said. With the key?
沒有那東西他做不了什麼 那他現在在哪？
He couldn’t do much without it. So where is he now?
我猜在北太平洋的某個地方
Somewhere in the Northern Pacific, I assume.
你給了他一艘航空母艦？
You gave him an aircraft carrier?
部長先生 我是武裝部隊總司令
I am the Commander in Chief of the Armed Forces, Mister Secretary.
那是我的航空母艦
It is my aircraft carrier
我想怎麼用就怎麼用
and I do with it as I please.
你早就知道會這樣
You knew this would happen.
我有懷疑過
I suspected.
你至少可以告訴我們一聲
You could have at least told us.
我剛說了 現在你們可以走了
I just did. And now you’re excused.
總統女士——就這樣
Madam President-- That will be all.
我不能告訴你
I couldn’t tell you.
這必須是我的責任 而且只能由我承擔
It had to be my responsibility and mine alone.
而且我得為亨特爭取時間
And I had to buy Hunt time.
有人可能會試圖阻止他
Someone could have tried to stop him.
他們或許不同意你的做法 但他們確實尊重你的權威
They may not agree with you, but they do respect your authority.
在這一切結束之前 會有人恐慌
Before this is over, someone will panic.
會有人試圖阻止我
Someone will try to stop me.
又是一場外勤
Another field trip.
你知道他在哪？我知道他最終會去哪
You know where he’s at? I know where he’s gonna end up.
給他個驚喜
Let’s surprise him.
[班吉] 記住 各國為了
[Benji] Now remember, governments would kill
知道我們對“塞瓦斯托波爾”號的瞭解 會不惜殺人
to know what we know about the Sevastopol.
這是個中情局監聽站
This is a CIA station
由經驗豐富的外勤特工運營 他們受過訓練以獲取情報 且絕不、絕不吐露
run by seasoned field agents trained to get information and never, ever give it.
千萬別向他們透露我們的真正任務 讓我來跟他們交涉
Tell them nothing about our real mission. Just let me do the talking.
你好
Hello.
需要幫忙嗎？我正有此意 是的
Can I help you? I certainly hope so. Yes.
我們在找SOSUS監聽站
We’re looking for the SOSUS listening station.
你們找到了 朋友 我是站長 比爾·東洛
You found it, friend. I’m the station chief, Bill Donloe.
我的妻子 塔皮莎
My wife, Tapeesa.
[班吉] 你好 近來可好？
[Benji] Hello. How do you do?
很高興認識你 比爾
Well, nice to meet you, Bill.
我們是英國地震研究所的研究人員——
We’re researchers from the British Seismological--
抱歉 你剛才說東洛？
I’m sorry, did you say Donloe?
沒錯 [班吉] 比爾
That’s right. [Benji] Bill.
威廉·東洛？
William Donloe?
蘭利的東洛？黑庫的東洛？
Langley Donloe? Black Vault Donloe?
[東洛] 就是他
The same.
你們是？
And you are?
我不敢相信……你們是認真…
I don’t believe... Are you ser...
這傢伙可是寫程式的傳奇人物
This guy is a coding legend.
他設計了蘭利的中情局大型機 黑庫
He designed the CIA mainframe at Langley. The Black Vault.
那是地球上最安全的資料庫 完全無法攻破
It’s the most secure database on the planet. It’s completely impenetrable.
嗯 如果真無法攻破 我就不會在這了
Well, if it were impenetrable, I wouldn’t be here.
那個資料庫在96年被攻破了
The Vault was breached in ’96
局裡當天就把我發配到了這兒
and the agency shipped me out the same day.
從那以後就一直在這
Been here ever since.
等等 也就是說你在這個島上待了……
Wait. So you mean to say you’ve been on this island for...
三十年
Thirty years.
出於好奇 你怎麼知道黑庫的？
Just out of curiosity, how do you know about the Black Vault?
這是絕密
That’s highly classified.
滴答滴答 滴答滴答
Tick-tock, tick-tock, tick-tock.
抱歉 請問兩位究竟是何方神聖？
Sorry. Who did you say you were?
直接告訴這人我們為什麼來吧
Just tell the man why we’re here.
東洛先生 比爾
Mr. Donloe. Bill.
就算我們能告訴你真相
Even if we could tell you the truth,
你也不會相信的 我不會信
you wouldn’t believe it. I wouldn’t.
關鍵在於我們需要訪問
The heart of the matter is that we need access
存取你們自2012年冬末以來的每一筆SOSUS資料
to all your SOSUS data from late winter 2012.
否則幾天後世界就不復存在了
Otherwise the world will cease to exist in a few days.
正在發生 對吧？
It’s happening, isn’t it?
實體
The Entity.
我多年來一直試圖警告人們 但是……
I’ve tried to warn people about it for years, but...
沒人聽
no one would listen.
你能幫我們嗎？
Can you help us?
我希望我能
I wish I could.
[盤子碰撞聲]
[dishes clattering]
[俄羅斯士兵] 請進
[Russian soldier] Please come in.
請隨便坐
Make yourself comfortable.
[飛行員1] 長官！醒醒！
[airman 1] Sir! Wake up!
醒醒 長官！
Wake up, sir!
我們有麻煩了 大麻煩
We got problems. Real problems.
怎麼回事？是“庫茲涅佐夫”號
What’s happening? It’s the Admiral Kuznetsov.
[飛行員1] 我們得離開這兒！
[airman 1] We got to get out of here!
我們進入老伊萬的威脅區了 夥計
We’re in Ivan’s threat zone, man.
看到“俄亥俄號”的蹤跡了嗎？沒有 長官 而且我們到返航油量點了
Any sign of the Ohio? No, sir. And we’re at bingo.
我再不調頭 燃料就不夠飛回母艦了
If I don’t turn around soon, we won’t have enough fuel to get us back to the boat.
電臺有什麼訊息？VHF全都是雜音
Anything on the radio? Nothing but static on VHF.
如果你的朋友們在發訊號 我們根本聽不見
If your friends are broadcasting a signal, we can’t hear it.
直接懸停
Just take us into a hover.
長官 我們到返航油量點了 只有五分鐘！
Sir, we are at bingo. Five minutes!
給五分鐘就行 拜託！
Just give me five minutes. Please!
我們可以通融一分鐘
We can give you one.
減速
Decel.
我們懸停幹什麼？得趕緊撤！
What are we doing in a hover? We got to bug out!
發現兩個敵機目標
Bogies at two.
他們亮出導彈了 夥計
They’re showing us their missiles, man.
這可是他們唯一的警告了
That’s the only warning we’re gonna get.
俄羅斯飛機……這簡直是第三次世界大戰的節奏 我們得走了！
Russian Aircraft... This is some World War III shit here. We got to go!
[飛行員2] 國際領空 沒有挑釁意圖
[airman 2] International airspace. No challenge.
我重複：絕無挑釁意圖
I repeat: No challenge is intended.
你到底要去哪？
Where the hell are you going?
[顫抖]
[shuddering]
[戰慄]
[shudders]
你在哪 伊森？
Where are you, Ethan?
[瑟瑟發抖]
[shivers]
你一定就是布萊德索艦長吧
You must be Captain Bledsoe.
而你一定瘋了
And you must be out of your mind.
如果我們沒出現 你們原本的計劃到底是什麼？
What exactly was the plan if we hadn’t shown up?
說實話 我還沒想那麼遠
You know, I really hadn’t thought that far ahead.
行吧
Okay.
才怪
Nope.
[伊森] 妮莉少將向你問好
[Ethan] Rear Admiral Neely sends her regards.
她跟我說會看到一顆綠色訊號彈
She told me to expect a green flare.
她可沒提過泰瑟槍
She never mentioned a Taser.
能解釋一下這到底是怎麼回事嗎？
Mind telling me what this is all about?
我的任務是機密的 哼
My mission is classified. Uh-huh.
我需要你帶我往北走
I need you to take me north.
繼續
Continue.
我在等一組精確的座標
I’m expecting a set of exact coordinates
透過摩斯電碼傳輸
via Morse code transmission.
你究竟指望怎麼在水底下收到這訊號呢？
And just how exactly do you expect to receive them down here?
你必須上浮到潛望鏡深度
You’d have to come to periscope depth.
升起天線
Raise the antenna.
掃描VHF頻段的低端訊號
Signal-scan the low end of the VHF band.
多久？十五分鐘
For how long? Fifteen minutes.
那會給俄羅斯人十五分鐘來精確定位我們的位置
That would give the Russians fifteen minutes to pinpoint our location.
從正午開始 之後每兩小時一次
Starting at noon, and every two hours after that,
直到我的團隊把座標發給我
until my team sends me those coordinates.
[布萊德索] 北邊是白令海 閣下
[Bledsoe] North is the Bering Sea, mister.
現在俄羅斯太平洋艦隊的潛艇全都在那上面
Right now every submarine in the Russian Pacific Fleet is up there.
我的首要任務是鎖定它們的位置
My primary mission is to lock down their positions
並弄清楚它們在搞什麼鬼
and ascertain what they’re up to.
我猜你知道答案
I’m thinking you know the answer.
[伊森] 那是什麼？那是聖馬修島
[Ethan] What is that? That’s St. Matthew Island.
那裡除了一箇舊SOSUS監聽站什麼都沒有
There’s nothing there but an old SOSUS listening station.
不 不 旁邊那個 那是什麼？
No, no, that right next to it. What is that?
[布萊德索] 那是“洛沙裡克”
[Bledsoe] That’s the Losharik.
你知道那是什麼嗎？
You know what that is?
是一艘微型潛艇 俄羅斯特種部隊的
It’s a mini-sub, Russian Special Forces.
給你頒個乖寶寶貼紙好了 先生
Get yourself a gold star, mister.
剛才一個多小時前 空中偵察在聖馬修島附近發現了它
Aerial recon spotted it off St. Matthew Island just over an hour ago.
它是從這個上面放出來的：
It’s deployed from this:
「別爾哥羅德」號 俄國海軍陣中最致命的核潛艇
The Belgorod.The deadliest submarine in the Russian Navy.
我的第二任務是找到那個雜種並將其處於受控威脅之下
My secondary mission is to locate that bastard and hold it at risk.
既然有“洛沙裡克” 說明它就在附近不遠
The Losharikmeans it’s somewhere close by.
那個島上有你的人
You have people on that island.
你的座標就是從那發出的
That’s where your coordinates are coming from.
你會幫我嗎？
Will you help me?
閣下……
Mister...
如果你想去捋北極熊的鬍子
if you want to poke the bear,
哼 你可找對人了
oh, you’ve come to the right man.
我想跟你的潛水長談談 長官
Like to speak with your divemaster, sir.
長官！
Chief!
是 長官
Yes, sir.
叫皮爾斯去海軍陸戰隊偵察營房迎接我們的客人
Have Pills meet our guest in the FORECON quarters.
[長官] 是 長官 這邊請 長官
[chief] Aye, sir. This way, sir.
[東洛] 正如我向這裡的各位解釋的
[Donloe] As I’ve explained to our friends here,
我沒有他們要的資料
I don’t have the data they want.
局裡對我的系統升級申請晾了十年
The agency ignored my request to upgrade our system for a decade.
結果有一天突然來了一隊人 毫無預兆
One day a team shows up, unannounced,
幾天之內就改裝了整個系統
and refits the entire system in a matter of days.
我想那是2012年冬天的事
I’m guessing this is the winter of 2012.
沒錯 老系統靠磁帶執行
Right. The old system ran on magnetic tapes,
備份在8英寸軟盤裡
backed up to 8-inch floppies.
這些都在後面的狗舍裡
These were in the dog shed out back.
這些箱子裡可能裝著你們
These boxes might contain the coordinates
所有人都在找的座標
you’re all looking for,
但我沒有讀取裝置
but I don’t have a reader.
那也在2012年被收走了
That was also taken away in 2012.
你指望他自己做一個
You expect him to build one.
我是來找座標的 不是來找箱子的
I came for coordinates, not boxes.
假設你找到了座標 我的人怎麼辦？
Supposing you find the coordinates. What happens to my team?
我會把座標帶給上級 我的人留在這
I will take the coordinates to my superiors. My men wait here.
等我們找到了我們要找的東西
When we have located what we’re looking for,
我的人就會離開 而你不會受到傷害
my men will leave and you will not be harmed.
如果換作是你 你會信嗎？
Would you believe that if you were me?
不 我不會
No, I would not.
給你一個小時把驅動器造出來
You have one hour to build the drive.
你叫什麼名字？
What’s your name?
科爾佐夫
Koltsov.
你的名字？艦長
Your first name? Captain.
科爾佐夫 我是格蕾絲 那是班吉
Koltsov, I’m Grace. That’s Benji.
我們能不能花五分鐘 像真正的人類一樣談談？
Could we just, for five minutes, be human beings?
不是俄羅斯人 也不是美國人 只是想再次見到摯愛的人
Not Russians, not Americans, just people that want to see our loved ones again.
我孤身一人 連條狗都沒有
I have no one. Not even a dog.
哼 你肯定沒有這把鑰匙
Well, you certainly don’t have this key.
那把十字形鑰匙 能讓持有者進入“波德科瓦”
The cruciform key that grants the holder access to the Podkova.
就算你們有了座標
Even if you have the coordinates,
沒有我們的幫助
you still can’t safely retrieve the Entity’s source code
你們也無法安全地找回智體的原始碼
without our help.
你們還有另一把鑰匙
You have another key,
對吧？
don’t you?
你們一直都有一把
You’ve had one all along.
你們缺的只是座標
What you don’t have are the coordinates.
而等你們造好驅動器
And when you build the drive,
我們就有了座標
we will have that.
好吧 換個方式
Okay, let’s try something else.
如果我告訴你 我們有個朋友
What if I told you that we have a friend
因為拒絕交出這把鑰匙而被自己的政府開除了呢？
who’s been disavowed by his own government because he refused to hand over this key?
我們的朋友現在就在外面 不受任何指揮鏈約束
Our friend is out there right now, independent from any chain of command,
正等著我們傳輸那些座標
waiting for us to transmit those coordinates.
他必會排除萬難
And he will stop at nothing
確保安然取得「波德科瓦」並利用其上存放的原始碼
to safely retrieve the Podkova and use the source code stored on it
徹底摧毀智體
to destroy the Entity.
這不僅僅為了某一個國家 而是為了全人類
And not for the sake of any one nation, but for all.
你還不明白嗎？智體正指望我們彼此猜忌
Don’t you see? The Entity is counting on us to distrust each other.
求你了……
Please...
讓我們完成使命吧
let us complete our mission.
我們並非敵人
We are not enemies.
換作是你 你會相信嗎？
Would you believe that if you were me?
[輕聲] 不會
[softly] No.
我想我也不會
I suppose I wouldn’t.
你們只有一個小時
You have one hour.
這是第七代抗壓服
This is the Mark VII pressure suit,
專為縮短深海潛水後的
specifically designed to reduce decompression time
減壓時間而設計
after diving profound depths.
它是透過氧氣與惰性氣體的特殊混合物來實現這一點的
It does this by means of an exotic mixture of oxygen and inert gases.
你需要進行長時間的呼吸適應 身體才能承受
You’ll need to do an extended breathe-up for your body to handle it.
我們具體在說哪種氣體？
Exactly what kind of gases are we talking about?
這是機密
That’s classified.
[皮爾斯] 假設你執行任務的時間在二十分鐘以內
[Pills] Assuming you’re on task for twenty minutes or less,
你的減壓時間就會從幾天縮短到幾小時
your time in decompression will be cut down from days to hours.
理論上是這樣 理論上？
Theoretically. Theoretically?
我們還沒在300英尺以下測試過第七代潛水服
We haven’t tested the Mark VII below 300 feet.
[潛水員1] 為了節省空氣 你需要快速下潛
[diver 1] To conserve air, you’ll need to make a fast descent.
這意味著必然會出現高壓神經綜合徵
Which means guaranteed HPNS.
高壓神經綜合徵
High Pressure Nervous Syndrome.
你應當預料到會有戰慄、
You should expect tremors,
抽搐、眩暈、
shakes, dizziness,
迷失方向以及精神錯亂
disorientation, and mental confusion.
而且這一切都發生在極端壓力之下
And all of it under extreme pressure.
[皮爾斯] 就算第七代潛水服按預期運轉
[Pills] Even if the Mark VII works as designed,
你們的混合氣體也不夠支撐緩慢上浮
you still won’t have enough mixture for a slow ascent.
這意味著你鐵定會得減壓病
That means you’re guaranteed to get the bends.
[皮爾斯] 你肌肉組織里的氮氣會膨脹進入血液
[Pills] Nitrogen in your muscle tissue expands into your bloodstream.
[潛水員2] 劇痛難忍
[diver 2] Excruciating pain.
全身抽搐
Convulsions.
肌肉徹底失控
Complete loss of muscle control.
你大概只有二十分鐘的時間趕到減壓艙
You’ll have maybe twenty minutes to get to the decompression chamber.
而如果沒有減壓艙……
And without the decompression chamber...
[皮爾斯] 你就死定了
[Pills] You’re a dead man.
[布萊德索] 又一輪甚高頻掃描結束了
[Bledsoe] Another VHF scan came and went.
如果你的朋友們在廣播
If your friends are broadcasting,
我們依然沒收到訊號
we still haven’t picked it up.
快點 快點 快點 快點 快點
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
那是馬廄裡的雪橇犬 準備開飯了
That’s the sled dogs out in the barn. It’s coming up to dinnertime.
我來告訴你一個小秘密 朋友
I’m gonna let you in on a little secret, friend.
這些磁碟裡根本沒有座標
There are no coordinates on any of these disks.
十四年前那次“翻新”？
That "refit" fourteen years ago?
怎麼看都透著一股掩蓋真相的惡臭
It had all the stench of a cover-up.
那個負責人對塔皮莎居高臨下
And the top man talked down to Tapeesa.
我很討厭那樣
I did not like that.
我從來沒跟他們提過這些備份
I never told them about these backups.
等他們走後 我自己把每一份備份都翻了個遍
And when they left, I went through every one of them myself.
唯獨有一件事非常扎眼
A lone event stood out.
那是一場大規模的海底內爆
A massive undersea implosion
就發生在他們來收走所有東西的大約一個月前
about a month before they arrived to take everything away.
照理說 我當時根本不懂這有什麼重大意義
Naturally, I didn’t understand the significance.
可是我記下了那組座標 然後
But I noted the coordinates and then
親手銷燬了僅存的這張磁碟
I destroyed the only disk.
[低聲] 你的意思是你知道“塞瓦斯托波爾”號的沉船點？
[quietly] Are you saying you know where the Sevastopolis?
精確到一平方米以內
Down to the square meter.
開飯啦
Dinnertime.
能讓我太太去照看一下那些狗嗎？
Can my wife please tend to the dogs?
這麼大噪聲我實在無法集中精力
I can’t concentrate with this racket.
[因紐特語] 座標
[in Inuktitut] The coordinates.
務必當心
Be careful.
我愛你
I love you.
我們還會再相見的
I will see you again.
她一個人忙不過來 我去！
She’s gonna need some help.I’ll go!
正好出去透透氣
I could use the air.
[俄語] 跟他們一起去
[in Russian] Go with them.
[布萊德索] 距離下一輪無線電廣播視窗還有五分鐘
[Bledsoe] Five minutes to the next broadcast window.
我們馬上就要潛入冰蓋下方並徹底失聯
We’ll be under the ice cap soon and lose all comms.
這將是我們最後的機會
This will be our last chance.
[雜音鏗鏘]
[clattering]
值班軍官 升起一號通訊天線
Chief of the Watch, raise number one comms antenna.
什麼？等等！等等 哈加爾
What? Wait! Wait, Hagar.
等等！
Wait!
等等 這是什麼？這是什麼？
Wait. What is this? What is this?
你阻止不了智體 伊森
You won’t stop the Entity, Ethan.
我不能讓你這麼做
I can’t let you.
東洛 去電臺！
Donloe, get to the radio!
傳送座標！
Send the coordinates!
[嘶嘶聲]
[hisses]
[無線電軍官] 指揮艙無線電！收到VHF莫斯電碼
[radio officer] Conn radio! VHF Morse code incoming.
無線電 外放
Radio, on speaker.
哈加爾
Hagar,
你花在……
you’ve spent too much...
上的時間
time
太多了！
on the Internet!
[哈加爾吃力喘息]
[Hagar straining]
[掙扎]
[struggling]
[俄語] 他在傳送座標
[in Russian] He’s sending the coordinates.
我們的人在聽著
Our people are listening.
屋頂要塌了 快出去
The roof is collapsing. Get out.
不 等等！
No, wait!
東洛呢？
Where’s Donloe?
東洛！
Donloe!
我們得走了！
We got to go!
[布萊德索] 你想要的座標
[Bledsoe] The coordinates you wanted.
恐怕你上錯船了
I’m afraid you’re on the wrong boat.
那裡距離好望角有2000英里
That’s 2,000 miles off the Cape of Good Hope.
在地球的另一端
On the other side of the world.
幾乎分毫不差
Damn near exactly.
“分毫不差 ”
"Exactly."
完全相反
Exactly the opposite.
以防俄羅斯人在竊聽
In case the Russians were listening.
非常高明
Very clever.
值班軍官
Officer of the Deck,
設定新航向：3-4-0
set a new course: 3-4-0.
[軍官] 舵向右15度 保持航向3-4-0穩舵
[officer] Right 15 degrees rudder, steady on course 3-4-0.
[舵手] 是 長官 舵向右15度
[helmsman] Aye, sir. My rudder is right 15.
值班軍官 水下接觸 方位1-0-0
Officer of the Deck, submerged contact, bearing 1-0-0.
在我們右舷消音瓦邊緣
On the edge of our starboard baffles.
外放 呈現俄羅斯奧斯卡II級潛艇的音響特徵
On speaker. Exhibiting tonals of a Russian Oscar II-class submarine.
值班長官 悄悄建立火控跟蹤組
Chief of the Watch, station the fire control tracking party silently.
[長官] 悄悄地 是 長官 好吧 算是完成了一個任務
[chief] Silently. Aye, sir. Well, that’s one mission accomplished.
我們找到了“別爾哥羅德”號
We found the Belgorod.
它正緊緊尾隨在後
It’s right on our ass.
無論你的任務要把你帶到哪去
Wherever your mission is taking you,
現在你把俄羅斯人也帶到那去了
now you’re taking the Russians there.
不 他們永遠不會知道我的目的地
No, they’re never gonna know my destination.
當我們到達那些座標時 我要你減速到十節
When we reach those coordinates, I’d like you to slow to ten knots,
把這艘船掉頭
turn this boat around
帶著俄羅斯人按原路返回
and take the Russians back the way we came.
那你的任務怎麼辦？
What happens to your mission then?
我會在掉頭的地方下艇
I’ll be getting off at the turn.
長官
Mister,
如果沒有我們的減壓艙 你必死無疑
without our decompression chamber, you’ll die for sure.
長官 你的減壓艙從來不在我們的計劃之內
Sir, your decompression chamber was never part of our plan.
哦
Oh.
好吧
Okay.
你的計劃究竟是什麼？
What exactly is your plan?
好吧
Okay.
[格蕾絲] 哈？
[Grace] Huh?
我？不！不 不 我不會 我不知道怎麼弄 我不知道怎麼弄
Me? No! No, no, I can’t. I don’t know how. I don’t know how.
當然
Of course.
行 做給我看
Yeah. Show me.
這是“左”
That’s "left."
[格蕾絲重複]
[Grace repeats]
“向前”
"Forward."
噢
Wooh.
[格蕾絲] 這個？“噢”是停嗎？
[Grace] On this? "Wooh" is stop?
噢
Wooh.
[格蕾絲] 好吧
[Grace] Okay.
這是幹什麼用的？
What’s this for?
北極熊？
Polar bear?
[說因紐特語 模仿槍聲]
[speaks Inuktitut, imitates gunshot]
這就是你的鑰匙 好嗎？接通電源
There’s your key, okay? Power on.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
[呼吸器嘶嘶作響]
[respirator hisses]
第七代潛水服的導航系統會帶你到達座標位置
The Mark VII’s guidance system will take you to your coordinates.
你所在位置的深度是500英尺
The depth at your location is 500 feet.
預計到達目標19分鐘 作業10分鐘
Figure 19 minutes to your target, 10 minutes on task.
記住：
Remember:
超過這個時間
Any longer than that
你的生還機率每秒都在下降
and your chances of survival decrease by the second.
別忘了：
And don’t forget:
上浮時必須持續呼氣
You must exhale continuously as you rise to the surface.
如果屏住呼吸 你的肺會炸裂
Hold your breath and your lungs will explode.
你要的VHF發射器
The VHF transmitter you asked for.
你的團隊應該能夠在兩英里半徑內定位你
Your team should be able to locate you within a two-mile radius.
給我照顧好它
Look after that.
祝你好運
Good luck.
照顧好我的潛水服
Take care of my suit.
[金屬拉伸聲]
[metallic straining]
聲納 到“別爾哥羅德”號的距離
Sonar, range to Belgorod.
長官 我有近場效應 太近了 無法測算
Sir, I have near-field effect. Too close to tell.
機動 按計程儀減速至十節
Maneuvering, slow to ten knots by log.
舵手 聽我口令 右滿舵
Helm, on my mark, right full rudder.
等候您的口令 艦長
Standing by for your mark, Captain.
[呼吸器嘶嘶作響]
[respirator hisses]
標記轉向
Mark the turn.
是 長官 我的舵是右滿舵
Aye, sir. My rudder is right full.
一路順風 閣下
Godspeed, mister.
[呼吸器嘶嘶作響]
[respirator hisses]
[無聲對白]
[no audible dialogue]
[水流聲]
[water rushing]
[呼吸器嘶嘶作響]
[respirator hisses]
[氣流嘶嘶作響]
[air hisses]
[呼吸器嘶嘶作響]
[respirator hisses]
魚雷發射管
Torpedo tube.
[瑟瑟發抖]
[shivering]
[無聲對白]
[no audible dialogue]
沒事了 沒事了
It’s okay. It’s okay.
在哪？
Where is it?
波德科瓦在哪？在這裡
The Podkova, where is it? Here.
你做到了 伊森
You did it, Ethan.
你做到了
You did it.
那接下來怎麼辦？
So what happens now?
現在……
Now...
我們去找加百列
we find Gabriel.
拿到盧瑟的毒丸
We get Luther’s poison pill.
然後消滅智體
And we kill the Entity.
伊森 我一直在想
Ethan, I’ve been thinking.
我們怎麼才能撤銷智體做過的一切？
How can we undo everything the Entity has done?
如果我們能控制它
If we could control it,
也許就能把世界從邊緣拉回來
maybe we could bring the world back from the brink.
格蕾絲……
Grace...
你到底會把這麼大的權力交給誰？
who on earth would you ever trust with that much power?
嗯 當然是你
Well, you, of course.
只有你
Only you.
我相信你註定要做這件事
I believe you were meant to do this.
不是我
Not me.
也不是任何人
Not anyone.
謝謝你……
Thank you...
帶我回來
for bringing me back.
舉手之勞
Nothing to it.
說來話長
It’s a long story.
我們還沒正式認識 我是——
We haven’t been formally introduced. I’m--
威廉·東洛 蘭利
William Donloe. Langley.
我們三十年前見過
We met thirty years ago.
差不多
Almost.
所以你就是他
So you’re him.
我知道我欠你一條命
I understand I owe you my life.
我不知道要如何彌補我對你人生造成的傷害
I don’t know how to make amends for what I’ve done to yours.
這取決於你怎麼看 朋友
That’s a matter of perspective, friend.
如果你三十年前沒有闖入資料庫 我可能現在還在那兒
If you hadn’t broken in the vault 30 years ago, I’d probably still be there.
我甚至可能覺得自己挺幸福
I’d probably even think I was happy.
我也絕不會找到這個真正給我帶來平靜的家
I never would have found the only home that’s ever brought me peace.
我當然也絕不會遇到我深愛的這個女人
And I certainly never would have met the woman I love.
沒什麼好抱歉的
There’s nothing to be sorry about.
我欠你一條命
I owe you my life.
[班吉] 我們將在時間耗盡時著陸
[Benji] We’ll be landing just as the clock runs out.
等我們到達時 智體將控制
By the time we arrive, the Entity will have control
全球九個自動化末日武庫
of the world’s nine automated doomsday arsenals.
並且它將為它控制的導彈加註燃料
And it will be fueling the missiles it controls.
但如果它想要生存 就得先找到一個能安全隱匿的地方 否則就無法發射
But it can’t launch until it has a safe place to hide if it wants to survive.
最安全的地方就是這裡
The safest place is here.
那是什麼？末日金庫 剛果堯瓦
What is that? The Doomsday Vault. Kongo Yowa.
[東洛] 這是一個絕密的、獨立的、靠太陽能供電的
[Donloe] It’s a top secret standalone, solar-powered,
防電磁干擾的、A級
TEMPEST-hardened, Level A
艾位元組資料伺服器
exabyte data server.
十億吉位元組的儲存空間
One billion gigabytes of storage.
這能存好多家庭錄影 [東洛] 嗯 你猜得差不多
That’s a lot of home movies. [Donloe] Well, you’re not far off.
它包含所有被認為值得儲存的人類積累知識
It contains all the accumulated knowledge deemed worthy of preservation.
而且它是完全遮蔽的
And it’s fully shielded.
[班吉] 完全不受任何形式的電磁能量影響
[Benji] Totally impervious to electromagnetic energy of any kind.
沒有任何資料進出
No transmissions in or out.
[東洛] 一個不可篡改的人類歷史方舟
[Donloe] An incorruptible ark of human history
專為在世界末日中存活而建造
built to survive the end of the world.
所以 如果智體鑽進那裡
So, if the Entity got in there,
它就能存活數千年
it could survive for thousands of years,
無論世界其他地方發生什麼
no matter what happened to the rest of the world.
[德加] 為什麼它會想要生存？
[Degas] And why would it want to survive?
消滅地球上所有的生命對它有什麼好處？
What does it stand to gain from wiping out all life on Earth?
諾亞和他的家人在大洪水前一定也問過這個問題
A question Noah and his family must have asked just before the flood.
[班吉] 這個反上帝把自己當成了上帝
[Benji] The Anti-God thinks it’s God.
[法語] 我們怎麼消滅它？
[in French] How do we kill it?
總是
Always
直奔主題 對吧？
right to the point, aren’t you?
這是包含盧瑟演算法的毒丸
This is the poison pill containing Luther’s algorithm.
這是“波德科瓦”
And this is the Podkova,
裡面則包含智體的原始程式碼
containing the Entity’s original source code.
兩者結合 它們將形成一種數字毒素
When combined, they will form a sort of digital toxin.
當上傳到網路空間時 這種毒素將攻擊智體
When uploaded to cyberspace, this toxin will attack the Entity
並改變它感知現實的能力
and alter its ability to perceive reality.
所以 將它與“波德科瓦”結合……
So, combine that with the Podkova...
我們就能欺騙謊言之主
We can deceive the Lord of Lies.
[法語] 但是……
[in French] But...
……總有個但是
...there’s always a but.
但是……
Mais...
我們沒有盧瑟的毒丸
we don’t have Luther’s poison pill.
加百列有
Gabriel does.
這就是為什麼我們可以確信他在末日金庫等我們
Which is why we can be sure he’ll be waiting for us in the Doomsday Vault.
[班吉] 一旦智體感染了盧瑟的演算法
[Benji] Once the Entity is infected with Luther’s algorithm,
它會以為自己正在進入樞紐的中央資料伺服器
it will think it’s entering the junction’s central data server
而實際上它會去這裡
when it will actually be going here.
這是什麼？
What is it?
[班吉] 小心 這非常嬌貴
[Benji] Careful, it’s very delicate.
不可能
It can’t be.
這是一個 5D 光學資料驅動器
It’s a 5D optical data drive.
掌中可容納360太位元組
360 terabytes in the palm of your hand.
[東洛] 我以為這只是理論上的東西
[Donloe] I thought these were just theoretical.
[Ethan] 曾經是
[Ethan] They were.
直到盧瑟做了一個
Until Luther built one.
如果智體是我們的燈神
If the Entity is our genie,
那麼這個光學驅動器就是我們把它困進去的瓶子
then this optical drive is the bottle we’ll capture it in.
這就引出了棘手的部分
Which brings us to the tricky part.
一旦進去
Once inside,
一旦它相信自己是安全的
once it believes that it’s safe,
智體就會啟動核彈發射
the Entity will initiate a nuclear launch.
我們必須在它這麼做之前拔掉這個驅動器
We have to disconnect this drive before it can do that.
我們有多少時間？
How long do we have?
大約……
Roughly...
[兩人] 100毫秒
[both] 100 milliseconds.
眨眼之間
The blink of an eye.
[班吉] 如果我們動手太早……
[Benji] If we do it too soon...
我們就困不住燈神
We won’t trap the genie in the bottle.
嗯 如果我們動手太晚……
Mmm. And if we do it too late...
我們就阻止不了智體發射
We won’t prevent the Entity from launching.
無論如何……
Either way...
[東洛] 如果我們在錯誤的時間拔下驅動器
[Donloe] If we pull the drive at the wrong time,
智體就贏了
the Entity wins.
[法語] 祝你好運
[in French] Good luck.
等等 如果末日金庫有電子遮蔽
Hang on. If the Doomsday Vault is electronically shielded,
智體怎麼進去？
how does the Entity expect to get in?
它指望我們放它進去
It expects us to let it in.
就像加百列指望我交出“波德科瓦”一樣
Just like Gabriel expects me to hand over the Podkova.
顯而易見 這兩件事我們都不會做
Neither of which we’d ever do, obviously.
對吧？
Right?
想想看 金庫有電子遮蔽
Think about it. The vault is electronically shielded.
任何訊號都進不去出不來
No signals get in or out.
必須有人走到金庫外面
Someone has to go outside the vault
才能把盧瑟的毒丸上傳給智體
in order to upload Luther’s poison pill to the Entity.
而且如果加百列想控制智體……
And if Gabriel wants to control the Entity...
他就必須上傳盧瑟的毒丸
He has to upload Luther’s poison pill.
你不是真打算把“波德科瓦”交給他
You’re not seriously gonna give him the Podkova
還讓他帶著毒丸逃跑吧
and let him get away with the pill.
這正是我打算做的
That’s exactly what I’m going to do.
加百列會成為團隊的一員 而他自己卻渾然不知
Gabriel will be part of the team and never know it.
這太瘋狂了！你在把智體放進金庫
That’s insane! You’re letting the Entity into the vault.
這正是它想讓你做的
That’s precisely what it wants you to do.
“命中註定 ”
"It is written."
[伊森] 是的
[Ethan] Yes.
這是我們戰勝加百列和智體的
And it’s the only chance we have
唯一機會
of beating Gabriel and the Entity.
萬億分之一的機會
One chance in a trillion.
伊森 想想你在幹什麼
Ethan, think about what you’re doing.
想想你是怎麼走到這一步的 想想世界是怎麼走到這一步的
Think about how you got here. Think about how the world got here.
你怎麼知道智體不是故意讓你找回“波德科瓦”的？
How do you know that the Entity didn’t want you to recover the Podkova?
也許它告訴你這是不可能的
Maybe it told you it was impossible
因為它知道那是你想聽的話！
because it knew that was the thing that you needed to hear!
你真是這麼想的嗎 格蕾絲？
Is that what you think, Grace?
我認為你是在拿世界的命運
I think you’re risking the fate of the world
以及數十億人的生命
and billions of lives
去賭一個眨眼的瞬間
on the blink of an eye.
是的 格蕾絲
Yes, Grace.
我就是在賭
I am.
若有別的選擇 我就會去選那個
And if there was another choice, I’d take it.
我知道你們都有所懷疑 我不怪你們
I know you all have your doubts. I don’t blame you.
但我們必須團結一致
But we have to stick together.
我們必須確保由格蕾絲
And we have to make sure that Grace
來拔下那個驅動器
is the one to disconnect that drive.
我？
Me?
一個優秀的扒手和一個偉大的扒手有什麼區別？
What separates a good pickpocket from a great one?
時機
Timing.
眨眼之間
Blink of an eye.
[班吉] 大家都去哪了？
[Benji] Where is everybody?
他們知道要發生什麼了
They know what’s coming.
他們都回家了
They’ve all gone home.
[安斯特朗] 我們無法準確預測智體現在的移動速度
[Angstrom] We can’t accurately predict how fast the Entity is moving now.
總統女士 亨特失蹤了
Madam President, Hunt is gone.
如果他沒死 他就落入俄羅斯人手裡了
If he isn’t dead, the Russians have him.
如果我們失去了對核武庫的控制
If we lose control of our arsenal,
我們就徹底失去了阻止智體發射的希望
we lose any hope of preventing the Entity from launching.
我們時間不多了！
We are out of time!
西德尼將軍……
General Sidney...
我們最有限的打擊選擇是什麼？
what is our most limited attack option?
[西德尼] 外科手術式核打擊
[Sidney] Surgical nuclear strikes
嚴格限定在受智體控制的
confined strictly to the command centers of the eight nations
八個國家的指揮中心
under the Entity’s control.
北京 伊斯蘭堡 倫敦
Beijing. Islamabad. London.
莫斯科 新德里 巴黎
Moscow. New Delhi. Paris.
平壤 以及特拉維夫
Pyongyang. And Tel Aviv.
傷亡情況
Casualties.
初次打擊的估計死亡人數
Estimated death tolls from initial strikes.
當然 隨後的核沉降物還會造成更多傷亡
And more later, of course, from the resulting nuclear fallout.
估計數字……呃 有所不同
Estimates, uh... vary.
顯然 轟炸八個不同國家的主要城市
Obviously the bombing of major cities in eight different countries
會引發前所未有的政治危機
would create an unprecedented political crisis.
這種危機很可能會導致一場持久的全球戰爭
One that would likely lead to a protracted global war.
從外交角度來看 做出一個……
It may be diplomatically prudent to make a...
姿態或許是明智的
gesture.
一個姿態？
A gesture?
犧牲我們國內的一座城市
Sacrifice one of our cities here at home.
我們已經擬好了一份名單
We’ve prepared a list.
[安斯特朗] 城市是按戰略和經濟重要性排列的
[Angstrom] Cities have been arranged by strategic and economic importance.
還有……
And...
……當然還有人口
...population, of course.
你們要犧牲一億人的生命……
You’d be sacrificing a hundred million lives...
來拯救七十億人
to save seven billion.
這不可能發生
This can’t be happening.
[西德尼] 總統女士
[Sidney] Madam President,
我們現在身處智體的現實之中
we are in the Entity’s reality now.
將死
And this is checkmate.
[重重腳步聲]
[stomps]
砲兵中士 把你的配槍給我
Gunnery Sergeant, I need your sidearm.
長官？
Sir?
聽見我的話了 孩子 交出來
You heard me, son. Hand it over.
主伺服器就在那邊
The main server’s through there.
班吉 格蕾絲 你們跟我來
Now, Benji, Grace, you come with me.
你們其他人 就在這等著
The rest of you, you just wait here.
不
Non.
[法語] 加百列在下面
[in French] Gabriel is down there.
讓我跟你們一起去
Let me come with you.
他的死期還沒到
His time will come.
那是伺服器室的門
That’s the door to the server room.
太暴露了
It’s too exposed.
你應該回其他人那邊去
You should go back to the others.
若加百列藏在裡面 你進去只有死路一條
If Gabriel is in there, he’ll kill you.
他必須帶著毒丸和“波德科瓦”離開這裡
He has to leave here with the pill and the Podkova.
我是可有可無的 你們倆都不是
I’m expendable. Neither of you are.
他說得對
He’s right.
照顧好你的團隊
Take care of your team.
[加百列] 你的最終清算！
[Gabriel] Your final reckoning!
三千萬噸當量
Thirty megaton yield.
我的人一鬆開那個按鈕 智體就無處可藏了
My man lets go of that button and the Entity has no place to hide.
那你呢？
And what happens to you?
我有一架飛機能帶我到絕對安全距離
I have a plane that’ll take me to minimum safe distance.
靠譜、類比 而且不會被雷達偵測到
Reliable, analog, under the radar.
我甚至帶了備用的 以防萬一
I even brought a spare. Just in case.
你真覺得毀了這裡
And you honestly believe destroying this place
就能阻止智體發射嗎？
will stop the Entity from launching.
我覺得它在虛張聲勢
I think it’s bluffing.
如果無法生存 它就不會毀滅世界；
It won’t end the world if it can’t survive,
而如果你不放它進去 它就無法生存
and it can’t survive if you don’t let it in.
現在把“波德科瓦”交出來
Now hand over the Podkova
我就放你走
and I’ll let you walk away.
我憑什麼相信你？因為我希望你
Why would I believe that? Because I want you
和你在乎的每個人
and everyone you care about
在我創造的世界裡長命百歲
to live long lives in the world I create
到時候智體將聽命於我
when the Entity answers to me.
你輸了 伊森
You’re beat, Ethan.
縱使躲過今天 改天換個地方你依然逃不掉
If not today, some other place, some other time.
只要我擁有這個
As long as I have this,
無論我走到哪 你都會跟到哪
wherever I go, you will follow.
而“波德科瓦”終究會落入我手中
And the Podkova will come to me.
這是命中註定的
That is written.
一切皆非命中註定
Nothing is written.
我看盧瑟未必會同意
I’m not sure Luther would agree.
現在
Now,
告訴我你贏了！
tell me I win!
你贏了
You win.
我喜歡聽這話
I like the sound of that.
再說一遍
Say it again.
才不要
Uh-uh.
哦 不
Oh, no.
雙手舉到我看得見的地方 混蛋
Hands where I can see them, dickhead.
交出來
Let’s have it.
還有多少時間？
Time?
18分鐘
18 minutes.
我認識你
I know you.
東洛
Donloe.
威廉·東洛
William Donloe.
我的妻子 塔皮莎
My wife, Tapeesa.
我不得不佩服你 亨特 你組建的這支隊伍真是頂尖
I got to hand it to you, Hunt. This is one crackerjack unit you’ve put together.
我敢說這會兒智體正在其虛擬短褲裡嚇得瑟瑟發抖
I’m imagining the Entity is shaking in its virtual shorts right about now.
我究竟需要了解什麼？到底是哪套方案？
What do I need to know about this, and what exactly was the play?
當前唯一策略就是把它親手交給他 並當場讓他離開
The only play is to give that to him, and let him go right now.
你想讓我把它交給他然後放他走
You want me to give this to him and let him go.
[伊森] 馬上 [基特里奇] 馬上
[Ethan] Right now. [Kittridge] Right now.
馬上 馬上……
Right now. Right now...
美國總統
the President of the United States
正準備將數以百萬計的生命從人間蒸發
is preparing to vaporize millions upon millions of souls.
全是因為這裡的伊森不相信任何人能安全地控制智體
All because Ethan here doesn’t believe that anyone can safely control the Entity.
這聽起來正常嗎？任何人覺得正常嗎？
Does that sound sane? To anyone?
也許你應該去問問“塞瓦斯托波爾”號的船員
Maybe you should ask the crew of the Sevastopol.
還有多少時間？17分鐘 長官
Time? 17 minutes, sir.
基特里奇 如果伊森沒有計劃 你不會站在這
Kittridge. You wouldn’t be here if Ethan didn’t have a plan.
誰能告訴我那個計劃是什麼
Whomever tells me what that plan is
就能拯救數百萬人的生命 你也能免於其他人的命運
will be sparing millions of lives, and you’ll be spared the fate of the others.
長官 我們時間不多了 我們得去絕對安全距離
Sir, we’re running out of time. We need to get to a minimum safe distance.
我們為什麼還站在這？
Why are we still standing here?
因為他在這裡 他就在這裡
Because he’s here and he’s here.
這意味著某種東西
And this means something.
隨時
Any second now
伊森就會告訴我它是什麼
Ethan’s gonna tell me what it is.
我認識這人很久了
I’ve known this man for a long time.
他絕不會讓他的寶貴團隊受到任何傷害
And he won’t want anything to happen to his precious team.
這就是模式 對吧？
And that’s the pattern, isn’t it?
你拒絕犧牲
You refuse to sacrifice
你親近的人
the ones you hold close.
這就是為什麼我們還站在這
That is why we’re still here.
結束了
It’s over.
這沒什麼好羞恥的
There’s no shame in it.
現在只需……
Now just...
告訴我我漏掉了什麼
tell me what I’m missing.
時間
Time.
好吧 就是現在！
Okay. Now!
[槍聲]
[gunfire]
加百列！
Gabriel!
帕里斯 加百列在那！動手殺了他！
Paris, Gabriel now! Kill him now!
[發動機轟鳴]
[engine revs]
德加！加百列！開槍打他 開槍打他 弄死他！弄死他！
Degas! Gabriel! Shoot him, shoot him, kill him! Kill him!
有本事就來抓我 伊森！
Catch me if you can, Ethan!
你去追他把毒丸拿回來
You go after him and get the pill.
我們去伺服器室放智體進來
We’ll get to the server room and let the Entity in.
伊森 我們會想辦法的
Ethan, we’ll figure it out.
你忘了那枚炸彈 核炸彈
You are forgetting the bomb. The nuclear bomb.
我們會想辦法的
We’ll figure it out.
伊森！班吉
Ethan!Benji.
去吧！這裡交給我
Go! I got this.
去吧
Go.
眨眼之間
Blink of an eye.
[伊森] 帕里斯！掩護 掩護！
[Ethan] Paris! Cover, cover!
亨特！
Hunt!
我還以為他不會走了
I thought he’d never leave.
我們會想辦法的
We’ll figure it out.
[發動機轟鳴]
[engine revs]
我們得走了 布里格斯
We got to go, Briggs.
自求多福吧 走
It’s your funeral. Let’s go.
一定有辦法解除武裝
There has to be a way to disarm it.
就算你能阻止它核爆
Even if you can prevent it from going nuclear,
你也阻止不了那些雷管爆炸
you can’t stop those detonators from exploding.
我們能在伺服器室的爆炸中倖存嗎？
Could we survive the blast from the server room?
除非有人留下來阻止炸彈達到臨界狀態
Only if someone stays behind and stops the bomb from going critical.
不管那人是誰 都絕不可能生還了
But whoever that is, they’re not going to make it.
[法語] 誰能倖免於難 誰又將命喪黃泉？
[in French] Who will live and who will die?
炸彈交給我們 你們其他人帶班吉去伺服器室
We’ll handle the bomb. The rest of you get Benji to the server room.
沒時間討論了 走
There’s no time to discuss it. Go.
[因紐特語] 我們還會再見面的
[in Inuktitut] I will see you again.
[班吉] 按住傷口
[Benji] Keep pressure on it.
[格蕾絲] 我按住了 我按住了
[Grace] I’ve got it. I’ve got it.
我留下來陪他們
I’ll stay with them.
我在伺服器室也幫不上忙
There’s nothing for me to do in the server room.
祝你好運
Good luck.
你在哪學的這手？
Where’d you learn to do this?
我可沒說我會
Never said I did.
這可不妙 是什麼？
This is not good. What is it?
如果我沒猜錯 是張力性氣胸
If I had to guess, it’s a tension pneumothorax.
那是什麼意思？胸膜腔內壓力積聚
What does that mean? Pressure building in the pleural cavity.
我的肺部塌陷了
My lung is collapsing.
如果我們不快點行動 就會窒息或心搏驟停
If we don’t act fast, it means suffocation or cardiac arrest.
你們倆誰有醫療經驗？
Do either of you have any medical experience?
[法語] 我殺人
[in French] I kill people.
這我能用得上
I can work with that.
格蕾絲 我要你入侵伺服器
Grace, I need you to hack the server
這樣我們就能放智體進來了
so we can let the Entity in.
拿上工具 去控制面板 帕里斯
Grab the tools, head to the panel. Paris.
[法語] 你得給我做手術
[in French] You have to operate on me.
我嗎？
Moi?
[英語] 首先我需要你堵住彈孔 做到不透氣
[in English] First I need you to plug the bullet hole, make it airtight.
[法語] 把它封緊
[in French] Close it tight.
繃帶
A bandage.
請給我繃帶
A bandage please.
我進去了 我該怎麼做？
I’m in. What do I do?
格蕾絲 我需要你找到電源開關……
Grace, I need you to find the power switch...
……連到伺服器的內部網路
...to the server’s internal network.
明白了 帕里斯
Got it. Paris.
[法語] 我的鎖骨……數到我的第二根肋骨
[in French] My clavicle... count down to my second rib.
現在……
Now...
……切個口子
...make an incision.
拿住這個
Hold this.
帕里斯
Paris.
[法語] 會沒事的
[in French] It’s going to be OK.
一口氣喝光
Bottoms up.
現在呢？
Now what?
筆……在包裡
Pen... in the bag.
壓力
Pressure.
把它拆開
Take it apart.
[英語] 格蕾絲 你找到開關了嗎？
[in English] Grace, did you find the switch?
找到了 [班吉] 好 把它關掉
Yeah. [Benji] Okay, shut it off.
[格蕾絲] 接下來呢？開啟面板
[Grace] What next? Open the panel.
[法語] 現在呢？[英語] 把這個插進切口裡
[in French] Now what? [in English] Push that into the incision.
快
Hurry.
[法語] 謝謝
[in French] Thank you.
謝天謝地
Oh, thank God.
德加 裡面情況怎麼樣？
Degas, how’s it going in there?
呃 這裡一切都在掌控之中
Uh, everything’s under control here.
好 把這個拿穩
Okay, hold this very steady.
但別把它拔出來
But don’t pull it out.
[加百列] 就像我說的 伊森
[Gabriel] It’s like I said, Ethan.
只要我有毒丸……
As long as I have the pill...
“波德科瓦”就會主動來找我
the Podkova will come to me.
等等 什麼？怎麼了？
Hang on. What? What is it?
我們或許有辦法脫困
We may have a way out of this.
這些地線是三重冗餘的
These ground wires are triple redundant.
如果我們同時切斷其中任意三根
If we cut any three of them simultaneously,
就能延遲這些雷管爆炸
we could delay these detonators from exploding.
或許能爭取足夠的時間讓人趕到伺服器室
Maybe long enough for someone to make it to the server room.
多久？
How long?
十秒 也許吧
Ten seconds. Maybe.
你覺得你能在十秒內跑到那扇門嗎？
You think you can make it to that door in ten seconds?
試過才知道 把棘輪扳手給我
Only one way to find out. Hand me the ratchet.
好 我進去了 接下來呢？[班吉] 我們還沒脫險呢
Okay, I’m in. What now? [Benji] We’re not out of the woods yet.
隨時我的血壓會驟降
Any minute now, my blood pressure’s gonna drop drastically
我會暈過去 所以我們得快點
and I’ll grow faint, so we need to work fast.
工具包裡有個接收器 一個帶兩個燈的銀色盒子
There’s a receiver in the tool bag. A silver box with two lights on it.
找到了
Got it.
我們需要把它接進伺服器的太陽能板上
We need to splice that into the server’s solar panels
做成一個天線
and make an antenna.
這樣我們就能知道
That way we’ll know
伊森什麼時候上傳毒丸
when Ethan’s uploading the poison pill.
對 懂了 現在是最棘手的部分
Yep. Got it. Now this is the really tricky part.
右下角有一捆
There is a bundle of blue, black, and red cables
藍色、黑色和紅色的電纜
in the lower right corner.
好吧 告訴我怎麼做
All right. Walk me through it.
我需要你按特定順序剪斷其中兩根線
I’m gonna need you to cut two of the wires in a specific order,
但無論你做什麼 千萬別剪……
but whatever you do, do not cut...
班吉！……紅色的
Benji! ...the red ones.
[瑟林] 總統女士 作為您的國防部長
[Serling] Madam President, as your Secretary of Defense
我請您注意CONPLAN 8044計劃
I direct your attention to CONPLAN 8044,
選定的打擊方案9.1
selected Attack Option 9.1.
對受智體控制的
A targeted nuclear strike on the command centers
所有八個國家的指揮中心進行有針對性的核打擊
of all eight nations now controlled by the Entity.
經修正後包括您選定要犧牲的那座美國城市
Amended to include the American city you’ve chosen to sacrifice.
「The Biscuit」
The Biscuit.
你跟你兒子談過嗎？
Have you spoken to your son?
我能跟他說什麼？
What would I tell him?
[瑟林] 身份驗證碼已確認
[Serling] Authentication code verified.
加油！
Come on!
加油 伊森
Come on, Ethan.
認輸吧
Know when you’re beat.
要不了多久你的人就全死光了
Any minute now your team will be dead.
智體也將無處可藏
And the Entity will have no place to hide.
[加百列] 我會把你逼入絕境
[Gabriel] I’m gonna run you into the ground.
“波德科瓦”將歸我所有
The Podkova will be mine
智體也將聽命於我
and the Entity will answer to me.
這只是時間問題
It’s only a matter of time.
[格蕾絲] 哎喲 [德加] 格蕾絲 我們覺得
[Grace] Ow. [Degas] Grace, we think
我們可以阻止這枚炸彈發生核爆
we can prevent this bomb from going nuclear,
但所有這些雷管都會爆炸
but all of these detonators will explode.
多大威力的爆炸？
How big a blast?
我們說的是多大威力的爆炸？
How big a blast are we talking?
[德加] 很大
[Degas] Big.
我們得盡可能幫伊森爭取時間
Ethan needs all the time we can give him.
除非萬不得已 千萬不要剪斷最後一根線
Do not make the last cut until we absolutely have to.
總統女士
Madam President,
發射已啟用
launch is now enabled.
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
做我們本該一開始就做的事
What we should have done in the first place.
命令美國戰略指揮中心切斷電源
Order U.S. Strategic Command Center to cut their power.
把我們的導彈全部離線
Take our missiles offline entirely.
關閉所有系統
Shut everything down.
總統女士 那會使國家完全失去防禦能力
Madam President, that would leave the country completely defenseless.
但能剝奪智體訪問地球上最大核武庫的許可權
But deny the Entity access to the largest nuclear arsenal on Earth.
現在 打電話吧
Now, make the call.
哦 謝天謝地
Oh, thank God.
長官 我們是地球上唯一一個
Ma’am, We are the only nation on Earth
有能力攻擊智體的國家！
with the power to attack the Entity!
而現在我們是世界上唯一一個有權做出選擇的國家
And now we’re the only nation in the world with the power of choice.
今天我選擇不發起攻擊
Today I choose not to attack.
總統女士 請三思
Madam President, think this through.
你在犯一個可怕的錯誤！
You are making a terrible mistake!
為了國家利益 請聽從理智
For the sake of the country, please listen to reason.
我正在這麼做
That’s precisely what I’m doing.
把我和戰略指揮部總部連線
Connect me with Strategic Command HQ.
[瑟林] 夫人 如果您不按下那個按鈕 數百萬人會死的
[Serling] Millions of people will die, ma’am, if you don’t push that button.
[沃爾特斯] 如果她按了 會有更多數百萬人死！
[Walters] And millions of other people will die if she does!
是什麼賦予我們決定誰生誰死的權利？
What give us the right to decide who lives and who dies?
[瑟林] 她宣誓過擔任美利堅合眾國總統
[Serling] She took an oath as President of the United States.
我們發射二十分鐘後 這些都不重要了！
Twenty minutes after we launch, none of that will matter!
我傾向於同意總統的看法
I’m inclined to agree with the President.
夫人 在我們站在這裡爭論的時候 智體正準備發動攻擊！
While we stand here arguing, the Entity is preparing to attack, ma’am!
諸位可以選擇生活在智體的現實中 我不選
You may choose to live in the Entity’s reality, gentlemen. I don’t.
請接通總統
Hold for the President.
奧弗頓將軍辦公室 戰略指揮部
General Overton’s office, Strategic Command.
奧弗頓將軍 我是總統 有一項非同尋常的命令要下達
General Overton, this is the President calling with an unorthodox command.
我需要你非常仔細地聽好我的指示
I need you to listen to my instructions very carefully
毫不猶豫地嚴格執行
and follow them to the letter without hesitation.
[眾人] 總統女士？我沒事 我沒事
[all] Madam President? I’m fine. I’m fine.
將軍！
General!
總統女士
Madam President.
[警報鳴響]
[alarm blares]
到現在為止 智體應該已經在給導彈加註燃料了
The Entity will be fueling its missiles by now,
但它在發射前仍然需要一個藏身之所
but it still needs a place to hide before it launches.
格蕾絲 跟我說 好了 我收到訊號了 完成了
Talk to me, Grace. I’ve got it. It’s done.
接收器已連線
Receiver’s connected.
好 我們開始
Okay. Here we go.
我們要把電源重新開啟
We’re gonna switch the power back on.
接收器已啟用 紅燈亮起
Receiver’s activated. Red light is on.
德加 情況怎麼樣？
Degas, how we doing?
很好 我們在拆除最後一個雷管
Great. We’re extracting the last detonator.
我們準備剪斷導火索了
We’re ready to cut the fuses.
倒計時四分鐘
Four minutes on the clock.
明白 四分鐘
Understood. Four minutes.
插入驅動器
Insert the drive.
[裝置發出提示音] [格蕾絲] 準備好了
[device chimes] [Grace] Ready.
[班吉] 現在 你要盯著接收器上的燈
[Benji] Now, you’re gonna watch the lights on the receiver.
當紅燈變成——
When the red light turns--
什麼？抱歉
What? Sorry.
當紅燈變成綠色時
When the red light turns green,
你就會知道伊森已經把毒丸連線到“波德科瓦”上
you’ll know Ethan has connected the pill to the Podkova
並且智體已經感染了盧瑟的演算法
and the Entity has been infected with Luther’s algorithm.
好 然後呢？
Okay. Then what?
然後你就要剪斷那根紅線 把智體放進來
Then you’re gonna cut that red wire and let the Entity in.
我們現在唯一需要的就是伊森拿到那個毒丸
All we need now is for Ethan to get that pill.
他會想辦法的
He’ll figure it out.
加油！
Come on!
[發動機轟鳴]
[engine whining]
[engine revs]
[費力喘息]
[strains]
[無聲對白]
[no audible dialogue]
我們只有一個人有降落傘！
Only one of us has a parachute!
祝你好運！
Good luck!
[發動機尖嘯 熄火]
[engine whines, stalls]
[東洛] 我們快沒時間了
[Donloe] We’re almost out of time.
剩10秒時我開始倒數三個數
At 10 seconds I’m gonna count backwards from three.
三 二 一 剪
Three, two, one, cut.
然後拼命朝那扇門跑
Then we run like hell for that door.
[班吉] 記住 當那個驅動器亮起時
[Benji] Remember, when that drive lights up
你就知道智體進來了
you’ll know the Entity’s inside.
你只有100毫秒
You have 100 milliseconds.
眨眼之間
The blink of an eye.
你在哪 伊森？
Where are you, Ethan?
伊森！
Ethan!
我是總統
This is the President.
他成功了
He did it.
這個混蛋居然真的成功了
That son of a bitch actually did it.
[錄音裡的盧瑟] 嗨 兄弟
[Luther on recording] Hello, brother.
如果你聽到這段話
If you’re listening to this,
這個世界依然存在
the world is still here.
而你也安然無恙
And so are you.
坦白說 我從未有過一絲懷疑
For the record, I never had a moment of doubt.
我就知道你能找到出路
I knew you’d find a way.
你總是能做到
You always do.
希望假以時日你能明白 這種生活
I hope in time you can see this life
並非常態下的偶然命運
was not some quirk of fate.
這是你的天職
This was your calling.
你的宿命
Your destiny.
一種關乎每一個生靈的宿命
A destiny that touches every living thing.
無論願不願意 我們都是自身命運的主宰
Like it or not, we are masters of our fate.
絕非命中註定
Nothing is written.
而我們的事業
And our cause,
無論再正義
however righteous,
也不及
pales in comparison
我們行為所產生的影響
to the impact
來得更加深遠
of our effect.
對美好未來的任何期望
Any hope for a better future
都源於憑意志讓那未來成為現實
comes from willing that future into being.
一個能反映我們內心善念程度的未來
A future reflecting the measure of good within ourselves.
火控！
Fire control!
[盧瑟] 而我們內心深處的一切良善……
[Luther] And all that is good inside us...
解除戒備
Stand down.
[路瑟] ……是以我們帶給他人的福祉來衡量
[Luther] ...is measured by the good
為他人所做的好事
we do for others.
我們共享著同樣的命運
We all share the same fate,
同樣的未來
the same future.
我們無數選擇的總和
The sum of our infinite choices.
其中一種未來建立在善良、信任
One such future is built on kindness, trust
以及相互理解之上……
and mutual understanding...
只要我們選擇
should we choose
接受它
to accept it.
不加質疑地往前衝……
Driving without question...
朝著一束我們看不見的光
towards a light we cannot see.
不僅為了我們珍視之人……
Not just for those we hold close...
嗨 媽媽
Hi, Mom.
……更為了那些我們永遠無緣相見的人
...but for those we’ll never meet.
希望你知道我永遠愛著你 兄弟
I hope you know I’ll always love you, brother.
我們還會再相見的
And I will see you again.
儘管我希望那一天不要來得太快
Though I hope it’s not too soon.
世界依然需要你
The world still needs you.
當然 他們永遠不會知道
Of course, they’ll never know it.
但我們知道
But we do.
我們這些活在
We who live and die
陰影中的生死之人
in the shadows.
本條資訊將在五秒後自毀
This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
祝你好運 伊森
Good luck, Ethan.
[《碟中諜》主題曲響起]
[ Mission: Impossible theme playing]